<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: musings | Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/blog/categories/musings/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-05T14:25:20-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is right?]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/what-right"/>
    <updated>2008-07-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/what-is-right</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There's an ideal of late that I've seen repeated within literature and movies that intrigues me. It is that of the men and women who have ideals. Ideals that they do whatever it takes to uphold. I find this a respectable character trait that I find myself wanting to mimic. To uphold.<br /><br />When you see wrong being done what do you do?<br /><br />When you see something happening that you do not agree with, what do you do?<br /><br />When there are ideals being upheld by the populace that you do not agree with, not becuase you are bias or jaded or just plain sick of, but because you KNOW beyond a shadow of a doubt that they are absolutely wrong, what do you do?<br /><br />Some choose to do more, some choose to hide, some choose to reason that they're not the one who can do anything about those things that hide in the dark of the mind and pervert the perception of those that would stand for what is right. But YOU know what is RIGHT. You KNOW what is WRONG. And even though you doubt yourself and how you feel about the subject of the matter, you KNOW in that inner most place that is untainted, unforgettable, unmoving... you KNOW.<br /><br />So do something about it! And the world will recognize as well, because they know as well, even though they may ignore it, even though they may reason it away... they know. And will support you if you are the one who champions the cause of WHAT IS RIGHT!<br /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Needs and Wants]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/needs-and-wants"/>
    <updated>2008-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/needs-and-wants</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For a long time I've thought that a major distinction in life that people must try to make is the difference between needs and wants. I've told many of my friends that if they just try to make this distinction in their own life, they will live a much happier, balanced life.</p>

<p>I was going through an old hard drive today and found many of my old writings on lots of different topics, but this one just jumped out at me as it is probably one of the most profound truths and holds some of the most engaging questions of life. The entry is dated 1-11-07:</p>

<p><cite>We've got to stop thinking that we are the only ones that matter.</cite>
<cite>Where does one find the strength to accomplish such a feat? What is the formula for molding one's self unto this task? We all want something greater than what we already experience in this life, but we must learn to separate that which we want, from that which is needed. </cite>
<cite>Define what is needed.</cite>
<cite>Can we tell by ourselves what is needed, or is it defined by those around us? Should it be defined by those around us, or by something greater? If by something greater, then what is that greater something? If by those around us, then whom?</cite></p>

<p>I've pondered on these things most of my conscious life, and still look for the answers. I doubt I will ever stop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alignment]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/alignment"/>
    <updated>2007-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/alignment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been having quite a time lately adjusting to this new life, priorities shifting all over the place, looking for a pattern to fall into, yet trying not to fall into a pattern. Women problems, travel problems, work, politics, and visions of the future, wondering which paths to take. Morality adjustments and sometimes not enough attention to my soul and the things that REALLY matter. But that's life in general. The changes that have started are sometimes scary and I continually re-evaluate my life and what matters to me. I've had periods of my life where I've been so secure in what I want and where to go and how to get there. But that feeling of security and steadfastness has been replaced by shifting sands underneath my feet and bright lights in every corner catching my attention, distracting me from what I really need and where I really should be. Time to start paying more attention to the things that matter most and cut out the clutter.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
