<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: New York | Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/blog/categories/new-york/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-05T13:48:29-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jerad goes to New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/jerad-goes-new-york"/>
    <updated>2007-07-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/jerad-goes-to-new-york</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So it's been a long time since I've posted, and there has been so much going on in my life. I've moved to New York City to work with Sony BMG making websites for rockstars. I gotta say, it's been a HUGE change for me. My calm, collected country life where I lived all alone in the woods with the ability to go camping in my back yard was replaced by the hustle and bustle of New York City, staying in a studio apartment next to the Empire State building.</p>

<p>I've been searching for an apartment, and there are lots available, but nothing seems to be what I really want and everything is just so expensive. There is one in Hoboken I'm going to be looking at this week and hopefully that will be it, but there is another one close to Hoboken, next to Washington Park, that Dave and I looked at today that was perfect. It's a little more expensive and there is a brokers fee so I may have to borrow from family to get into the place. I really don't want to do that, and would rather have the place in Hoboken so that I can feel like I'm doing it all on my own, but then my bank account still hasn't received my first paycheck from Sony and I'm worried that they haven't setup my direct deposit yet. That means they've mailed my check and I won't get it until Monday or Tuesday, then I have to get it deposited into my account back home. Only after that will i be able to setup the rent.com escrow account in order to get the keys form the guy who owns the place in Hoboken. He's living in Athens Greece, so we have to do it this way. So as you can imagine, with only 9 days or so to get moved and into a place, I'm stressing.</p>

<p>However, there are a few other possibilities, like Dave getting the same benefits as myself and hanging with him wherever Sony puts him, but that's not going to happen before I have to get out of the place I'm at now. So I guess I'm really banking on this place in Hoboken... ah stress...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
