<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: San Francisco | Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/blog/categories/san-francisco/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-29T10:43:45-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Californication]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/californication"/>
    <updated>2008-07-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/californication</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Drupal, you've done it again... become the vector of change in my life by presenting me with opportunities that are seemingly too good to be true. Last year it was New York and Sony BMG. This year it's San Francisco and a start-up called ParentsClick Network. Just when I thought things couldn't get any better and that maybe I've hit the height of reaching my dreams in life, another one comes within my grasp, and giving in to my free spirit, I jump at the chance to make a dream a reality.</p>

<p><a href="http://tedserbinski.com/">Ted Serbinski</a> is a guy whose progress I've followed since that first <a href="http://jeradbitner.com/node/11">Lullabot class in Rhode island</a>, less than two years ago (1/15/07) when the world of Drupal really opened up to me. He was a Lullabot at the time, teaching theming and some jQuery. He <a href="http://tedserbinski.com/2007/05/24/i-have-left-lullabot">left Lullabot</a> later that year to start a journey into entrepreneurship (and <a href="http://tedserbinski.com/tags/mothersclick">MothersClick</a>) that has started to pan out nicely. I've great respect for his coding skills and believe in his business sense. So when he approached me about a job working with him in San Francisco, a place I've always wanted to live, I was very excited.</p>

<p>After a week of vacation, taking time to think about my priorities while spending time with family and friends in PA, and then meeting with Ted's business partner, <a href="http://www.mothersclick.com/management">Dietrich von Behren</a> who is the Co-founder &amp; Chief Strategy Officer of MothersClick, I felt confident enough to make the jump and reach for a star on the other side of the country.</p>

<p>My last day at Sony BMG is August 7th, 2008. I'll be heading back to PA to spend some more time with my family and friends and then back to Jersey to take care of getting rid of as much of my worldly possessions as possible. Then the week of the 18th Dave and I will be taking a cross country trip to San Francisco along RT 80. We're still looking for good places to stop along the way, so if you have any suggestions that would be wonderful! I'm also still looking for a temporary place to crash in San Fran while I get the lay of the land and figure out where it makes sense to park myself for a year (read: sign a lease).</p>

<p>All in all, I'm very optimistic and I really feel this is the right move. Not only because I can live one of my dreams, but also to learn about starting a business, and everything that entails. Not to mention becoming a better programmer under the tutelage of a master! Wish me luck!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
