<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-06T16:54:33-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://jeradbitner.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[new-post]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/03/12/new-post/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T20:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/03/12/new-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Replicate and share]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/27/replicate-and-share/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-27T04:52:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/27/replicate-and-share</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a child I learned how to speak. The sounds I heard my parents produce helped to form coherent thought patterns in which to relate with the world around me. No, yes; good, bad; dog, cat; hot, cold; all sounds that came to mean something to a normal human being. I replicated their sound and shared.</p>

<p>As I grew, I heard birds, singing in the fields. I learned their whistles and they came to me filling me with the wonder and joy of nature. I replicated their sound and shared.</p>

<p>As I grew, I heard songs at church, worshipping an ideal that was greater than oneself. I learned to sing with the choir and through my song, shared those ideals with more people. I replicated their sound and shared.</p>

<p>As I grew, I heard songs on the radio. I learned them and played my instruments. I learned enough to join a band where we played the songs we had learned for people to enjoy. I replicated their sound and shared.</p>

<p>As I grew, I heard songs on the internet. I learned them, learned to love them, and shared them with my friends so that they could love them too. I replicated their sound and shared.</p>

<p>When I went to jail, untried by my government, for doing what has come naturally to me since I came into this world; replicating the sounds I heard, I cringed at the cries of those around me. I replicated their sound&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrate Flickr or Facebook photos to Picasa/Google+ easily]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/14/migrate-flickr-to-picasa-easily/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-14T16:33:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/14/migrate-flickr-to-picasa-easily</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I found a great way to transfer photos from <a href="http://www.flickr.com/">Flickr</a> or <a href="http://www.facebook.com/">Facebook</a> to Picasa/<a href="http://plus.google.com">Google+</a> quickly and easily, keeping albums intact using Mac OS X iPhoto &#8216;11.</p>

<p><strong>Step 1:</strong><br>
Download and install the <a href="http://picasa.google.com/mac_tools.html">Picasa Web Albums Uploader</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Step 2:</strong><br>
Within iPhoto, select iPhoto > Preferences and then the Accounts tab to connect to your Flickr account.<br>
<img src="https://img.skitch.com/20120215-epm1hsd8fm9jy44ame3aaaytdh.png"></p>

<p><strong>Step 3:</strong><br>
Within iPhoto, select the Flickr icon in your sidebar.<br>
<img src="https://img.skitch.com/20120215-bc5xsu5q1259gftmdkceq3yfy6.png"></p>

<p><strong>Step 4:</strong><br>
Within iPhoto, select the Flickr album you want to move and double click to open in order to make sure iPhoto retrieves all of the photos.<br>
<img src="https://img.skitch.com/20120215-k4re65p6j4s14py52k8x9d5ath.png"></p>

<p><strong>Step 5:</strong><br>
Within iPhoto, select File > Export and use the &#8220;Picasa Web Albums&#8221; tab to export your selected Flickr album right into Picasa.<br>
<img src="https://img.skitch.com/20120215-xfpx814n6d5xtwc6jphe1rja2d.png"></p>

<p>Upon signing into your Google Plus account, and viewing your albums, you should now see the exported album available.
<img src="https://img.skitch.com/20120215-ejkj42q1xyqf5q5ju4jnegthy.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baby Day! (Act I)]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/10/baby-day-act-i/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-10T17:27:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/10/baby-day-act-i</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2.9.12 - 11:45pm
Jenny wakes me up with, &#8220;I think my water broke!&#8221;
I groggily look over at her and ask, &#8220;Are you sure?&#8221;
&#8220;Yeah, pretty sure&#8221;, she says.
&#8220;What time is it?&#8221; I ask her.
&#8220;11:45&#8221;.
&#8220;What? Uhg.&#8221; I had gotten about two and a half hours of sleep by this time, having gone to bed early to try and kick my oncoming head cold. &#8220;Did you call Katie?&#8221; Katie is our birthing companion, whom we took HypnoBirthing courses with months earlier.
&#8220;I am going to now&#8221;, Jenny tells me.
&#8220;Do you want to go to the hospital?&#8221;
&#8220;No, let&#8217;s just see what happens. Go back to sleep.&#8221;
I promptly fall back asleep, but hear her stirrings through dreams of a strange birth in which the baby is born in a tub and no one at the hospital cares. I hear snippets of a conversation on the phone, the tub water running, a hair dryer blowing, a shower, and repeatedly telling the dog, Dante, to go back to bed when he wined because Jenny was in a different room.</p>

<p>2.10.12 - 5:45am
Jenny laid across the bed, obviously in pain and emotional. I asked her a few questions about how she felt, and how often her surges were. They were about 3 minutes apart. Hating to see my wife in pain, I decided we should go.
&#8220;Let&#8217;s get going hun. Do we have everything ready?&#8221;
&#8220;Everything is already in the car,&#8221; she tells me.
I started to pack my computer and some cords, books and my baoding balls, put the dog in his kennel, grabbed the keys and we got into the car and started on our way to the hospital, texting work, friends and family as we went.
Almost to the bottom of the mountain, Jenneys says, &#8220;Crap! I forgot the HypnoBirthing materials on the coffee table.&#8221;
&#8220;Should we go back?&#8221; I ask.
&#8220;Yeah, we better get them.&#8221;
So we turned around at Manitou Springs and headed back to the house, about 25 minutes away at this point. When we get there, we grabbed the books and immediately headed back down the mountain pass.</p>

<p>On the way to the hospital, the morning sky was just amazing.
<img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7199/6866465775_ee6c5865e2_z.jpg"></p>

<p>Sitting in traige the nurse (whose name was also Jenney, with wonderful sparkly shoes) tested dilation and for amniotic fluid but we were only a little over two centimeters and couldn&#8217;t find evidence of amniotic fluid. Katie, our birthing companion who was also our HypnoBirthing instructor arrived and we took a walk to the cafeteria. Going was slow as Jenney&#8217;s surges were pretty close together and she had to stop and hold onto me until they passed.
<img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7056/6866467167_79bb6d2988_z.jpg"></p>

<p>We got some breakfast and ate and then walked around the hospital for a while. An hour after sending us out for a walk we returned and re-tested. Still no fluid and still under four centimeters, which is the minimum dilation for admittance. So we walked again, found some steps, and walked all over the place. Another hour later, they decided we should go home since we apparently weren&#8217;t progressing. So Katie, Jenney and I all left.</p>

<p>We decided to go to the store, Costco, and walk around. My mother called and wanted an update so I gave her one and asked her about her own pregnancy with me. Jenney had a pretty nasty cold for the last three weeks, and the nurse had mentioned that the baby would have a bit of a boost because of Jenney&#8217;s anit-bodies, which could contribute to a very healthy immune system. I have always had an amazing immune system, about three times as strong as Jenney&#8217;s, so I asked my mom if she had a cold or anything of the sort while pregnant with me. She said she hadn&#8217;t, but that she has also always had a very strong immune system. It will be interesting to see how strong Viola&#8217;s will be.</p>

<p>Jenney was wearing her &#8220;I grow humans. What&#8217;s your superpower?&#8221; shirt as we walked around the store, and she got quite a few stares, and some comments about her shirt. However, after increased stares, and after standing still together after another surge, I took a good look at her shirt and realized that her left breast had leaked through on her shirt, causing a wet spot. I told her and she said, &#8220;No, I must have just leaned on something.&#8221; In any case, I&#8217;m sure we looked <em>very</em> white trash at this point and just wanted to leave the store, though I also thought it pretty funny.</p>

<p>We left the store and started heading back home, but the surges started coming more frequently again, and stronger, so we decided to instead stop at my friend John Ferris&#8217;s house. I felt bad just dropping by unannounced, but he had already mentioned that if we needed anything to just let him know. Plus I had been planning on working from his house that day, so I knew he would be home. John has a great little spare room in his finished basement, so we stopped, put a four pound bag of frozen berries that we had picked up at Costco in his freezer, and put on some relaxing music for Jenney in the spare room.</p>

<p>We stayed for about two hours when the surges started becoming more than Jenney could bare. After reading some HynoBirthing materials to her, and being unable to calm her, we decided to go back to the hospital. I called Katie and had her meet us there.</p>

<p>Back at the hospital, they checked Jenney again, but she still wasn&#8217;t admittable. And so we walked some more. Her contractions were very strong still, but without being far enough along, we had to just bear with it, walk for an hour, go back and get checked.</p>

<p>Finally, around 4:30 or 5pm, they decided we were far enough along to be admitted. I&#8217;m not sure if dilation was enough, or they could see that contractions just were not going to stop, and that they were still intense, but it was s huge relief to just be admitted to a room and know that we were going to be there until the birth.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nginx: do not cache logged in Drupal or WordPress users]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/09/nginx-do-not-cache-logged-in-drupal-or-wordpress-users/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-09T17:29:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/09/nginx-do-not-cache-logged-in-drupal-or-wordpress-users</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A while ago I changed all of my domain names to <a href="http://namecheap.com/">Namecheap</a> and migrated my Drupal and Wordpress sites to <a href="http://www.linode.com/">Linode</a>. I followed some excellent instructions from <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/q0rban">James Sansbury</a> (soon to be a Lullabot article) and some of his <a href="https://github.com/q0rban/nginx-drupal">Nginx configuration files</a>. This worked great for my Drupal site (heh - which was this site that I then <a href="blog/2012/01/29/using-node-dot-js-to-convert-drupal-to-jekkyl/">converted to Jekkyl</a>) and my <a href="http://jenneymarie.net/">wife&#8217;s WordPress site</a>.</p>

<p>However, when my wife started using her blog on my fancy new Nginx setup with PHP-FPM, she noticed that when she created posts one after the other, they were overwriting eachother, effectively creating a new revision of the same post instead of creating a new one. I knew that this was because of the caching, but was still too new to Nginx to know exactly what to do about it.</p>

<p>Again, James to the rescue! He pointed me in the right direction and I got it working. Here&#8217;s what I did.</p>

<p>One of the relevant pieces of James&#8217; setup, is this line within his <a href="https://github.com/q0rban/nginx-drupal/blob/master/nginx.conf#L63"><code>/etc/nginx/nginx.conf</code></a>:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>http {
</span><span class='line'>...
</span><span class='line'>  ##
</span><span class='line'>  # Virtual Host Configs
</span><span class='line'>  ##
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  include /etc/nginx/conf.d/*.conf;
</span><span class='line'>  include /etc/nginx/sites-enabled/*;
</span><span class='line'>}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>And then within <a href="https://github.com/q0rban/nginx-drupal/blob/master/conf.d/session_cookie.conf"><code>/etc/nginx/conf.d/session_cookie.conf</code></a> he searches for the cookie that Drupal sets when you log in:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'># Determine if a Drupal session cookie is present
</span><span class='line'>map $http_cookie $logged_in {
</span><span class='line'>    default 0;
</span><span class='line'>    ~SESS 1; # Drupal session cookie
</span><span class='line'>}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>To this, I added a search for the wordpress cookie as well:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'># Determine if a Drupal session cookie is present
</span><span class='line'>map $http_cookie $logged_in {
</span><span class='line'>    default 0;
</span><span class='line'>    ~SESS 1; # Drupal session cookie
</span><span class='line'>    ~wordpress_logged_in 1; # Wordpress session cookie
</span><span class='line'>}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The last piece is telling your site to bypass the cache if <code>$http_cookie</code> is set:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>location / {
</span><span class='line'>  ...
</span><span class='line'>  # If client is logged in we bypass cache
</span><span class='line'>  fastcgi_cache_bypass $logged_in;
</span><span class='line'>  fastcgi_no_cache $logged_in;
</span><span class='line'>  ...
</span><span class='line'>}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>A quick <code>sudo service nginx restart</code> and our WordPress site is working much better!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Darkness &amp; Light]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/07/darkness-and-light/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-07T14:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/07/darkness-and-light</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2d0g2v3H3i0V0o1t2O0d/light-dark.png" alt="Dark &amp; Light" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angel of fire]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/06/angel-of-fire/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-06T18:33:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/06/angel-of-fire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>Angel of fire, wings of light
</span><span class='line'>  Visit me in my dreams tonight
</span><span class='line'>  Tell me of love and burning desire
</span><span class='line'>  Caress my lips, set me on fire
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>Angel of fire, eyes so bright
</span><span class='line'>  See through my soul, feel the fright
</span><span class='line'>  Singe my heart and look for the liar
</span><span class='line'>  Scar on my sould cleanse with your fire
</span><span class='line'>  Transcendance lost on the blackening shame
</span><span class='line'>  Licked by lips that are black from the flame
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>Angel of fire, cleanse me just right
</span><span class='line'>  Leaving your mark steal through the night
</span><span class='line'>  Tease my mind leaving desire
</span><span class='line'>  Tease my heart scarred by your fire
</span><span class='line'>  Knowing we'll never ever be the same
</span><span class='line'>  Learn from our past, never do this again</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>AUG &#8216;04</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[todo list in node.js and geektool]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/05/todo-list-in-node-dot-js-and-geektool/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-05T13:59:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/05/todo-list-in-node-dot-js-and-geektool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve long had a quick shell script that was a simple todo list based on Jerod Santo&#8217;s <a href="http://blog.jerodsanto.net/2010/12/minimally-awesome-todos/">Minimally Awesome Todos</a>. It&#8217;s very minimal, and quite awesome indeed. Even more than loving how minimal it is, I really liked displaying my todos on my desktop through <a href="http://projects.tynsoe.org/en/geektool/">GeekTool</a>.</p>

<p>Then I stumbled onto a <a href="https://github.com/vesln/todo">Node.js version</a> of a todo list and thought I&#8217;d give it a shot. I got it setup, but when I wanted to try to display the output through GeekTool, I failed. So I delved into todo list code a bit more and learned quite a lot!</p>

<p>My <a href="https://github.com/vesln/todo/pull/3">first attempt</a> was to simply write the output of the <code>todo ls</code> command to a file. I got an immediate response from the maintainer, <a href="https://github.com/vesln">Veselin Todorov</a> and was encouraged to change the command from <code>write</code> to <code>export</code> and write up a test for the new command as well.</p>

<p>I succeeded in <a href="https://github.com/vesln/todo/pull/4">converting the <code>write</code> command to <code>export</code></a>, and fixed up a small bug with the path of the file I was writing to by default, but thus far have completely failed at writing a test to confirm that the file was written.</p>

<p>The project is currently using <a href="http://sinonjs.org/">Sinon.JS</a> for testing, and even though the API seems pretty robust, and the examples coherent, I&#8217;m simply failing at figuring out how to test file creation with it. So far all I have is a stub:</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/1747985.js?file='></script>
<noscript><pre><code>  describe('.export()', function(done) {
    it('should write todos to a file', function(done) {

    });
  });</code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>However, it is working well without a test at this point, and I have a pretty todo list on my desktop! :)</p>

<p><img src="https://img.skitch.com/20120205-q32piq2918kutm1autmh6yby4m.png" alt="GeekTool Todos" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New blog command and some style updates]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/05/new-blog-command-and-some-style-updates/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-05T13:39:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/05/new-blog-command-and-some-style-updates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love Github. The more I use it, the more I love it. As a form of endearment, I&#8217;ve updated the style of this blog to look a little more like Github than default Octopress. Simple, clean, fun.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve also been looking for a quicker way to blog on a whim, and having to switch into my octopress directory, and then type <code>new_post["title of my post"]</code> was still just two steps too much. So I pulled up my <code>.bash_profile</code> and started scripting. Here&#8217;s what I came up with:</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/1747860.js?file='></script>
<noscript><pre><code>###########
## Blogging
function new_post {
  cd /Users/sirkitree/github/octopress
  rake new_post[&quot;$1&quot;]
}
alias blog=&quot;new_post&quot;</code></pre></noscript></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML5 Photobooth]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/01/30/html5-photoboot/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T09:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/01/30/html5-photoboot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After reading an <a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/news/2012/01/hands-on-building-an-html5-photo-booth-with-chromes-new-webcam-api.ars">article</a> about the experimental support for WebRTC getting put into the latest version of browsers, my buddy <a href="https://plus.google.com/102577299588201077107/about">David Burns</a> was inspired to write a quick app called <a href="http://html5photobooth.com/">HTML5 Photobooth</a>.</p>

<p>Code can be found here: https://github.com/davexoxide/HTML5-Photobooth</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Node.js to convert Drupal to Jekkyl]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/01/29/using-node-dot-js-to-convert-drupal-to-jekkyl/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-29T15:54:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/01/29/using-node-dot-js-to-convert-drupal-to-jekkyl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve gone and revamped my blog again.</p>

<p>The current new hotness has been <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki">Jekkyl</a> of late, ever since GitHub came out with it&#8217;s <a href="http://pages.github.com/">Pages</a> feature. My first awareness of it was around September 2011 when <a href="http://developmentseed.org/">DevelopmentSeed</a> converted their .org page to Jekkly and <a href="http://developmentseed.org/blog/2011/09/09/jekyll-github-pages/">wrote about it</a>. I started playing with it almost immediately when I had downtime during <a href="http://www.lullabot.com">Lullabot</a>&#8217;s <a href="http://2011.doitwithdrupal.com">Do it with Drupal</a> conference. Sacreligious? Whatever, it was something new to learn.</p>

<p>Then quite recently <a href="http://walkah.net/blog/new-year-new-blog/">Walkah.net</a> moved to Jekkyl and renewed my interest when he released the <a href="https://github.com/walkah/walkah.net/blob/master/_import/drupal.rb">Ruby script</a> he used to convert his simple Drupal blog into YAML for use with Jekkly. That looked interesting so I put it in my backlog.</p>

<p>Shortly after, I started getting some <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/mikl/status/159634667702722562">flak</a> from <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/mikl">@mikl</a> for not paying attention to my Drupal.org issue queue for the <a href="http://drupal.org/project/flag_friend">Flag Friend</a> module and as I interacted with and him, found that he was using <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> for <a href="http://mikkel.hoegh.org/">his personal blog</a>. Octopress is a quick way to get started using Jekkly, and I like quick.</p>

<p>So I put these two sources of inspiration together and it gave me reason to revisit Walkah&#8217;s Ruby script. After a few hours of trying to get the MySQL Ruby Gem working with the version of MySQL I have that comes with MAMP, I gave up and decided to just <a href="https://github.com/sirkitree/sirkitree.github.com/blob/master/_import/drupal.js">rewrite the script into Node.js</a>, which I&#8217;ve been trying to learn more about lately.</p>

<p>The end result is all of my posts from JeradBitner.com converted into YAML format for use with the Octopress system which uses Jekkyl to generate your pages and can be convieniently hooked up to GitHub Pages in order to quickly create content with a few simple commands. (Whew! Try saying that to your wife without sounding bat-shit crazy!)</p>

<pre><code>$&gt; rake new_post['Title of your post']
</code></pre>

<p>  Then write your post of course.</p>

<pre><code>$&gt; rake generate
</code></pre>

<p>  Which runs Jekkly and converts all of your YAML to HTML and puts the files in the correct place.</p>

<pre><code>$&gt; rake preview
</code></pre>

<p>  This starts up a local server so you can see your new post at localhost:4000.</p>

<pre><code>$&gt; rake deploy
</code></pre>

<p>  Which commits the generated files to your GitHub repository and pushes them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Images]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2011/04/25/images/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2011/04/25/images</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These are from high school. Guess you&#8217;d call that about the height of my creativity - or at least when I had the time to do all of this instead of worrying about a paycheck.</p>

<iframe align="center" src="http://www.flickr.com/slideShow/index.gne?set_id=72057594056358798&" frameBorder="0" width="690" scrolling="no" height="690"></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poems]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/poems"/>
    <updated>2011-04-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/poems</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These are also all pretty old and come from the angst and passions of a teenager. I&#8217;ve grow less intense, it seems, over the years as I don&#8217;t seem to have the knack of this anymore - if ever I really did. Some of it I still find pretty fun, though it&#8217;s a bit harder to appreciate in a digital medium since part of what made these so interesting was in the way I wrote them. Strange spacings, capitalization&#8217;s, and pictographs along with the structure were all part of my art form.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beauty.]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/poems/beauty"/>
    <updated>2011-04-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/poems/beauty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre>
           In the eye of the beholder?
  Maybe.                                                    Not?
                      Well...?
           For sure, are my wants.                  Love,
beauty - I behold.
                            You?
           Oh! Matters to me, what you think.
  Love me?                   Love,     me?
                                Yes!
       For a long time, ifn't life.
Teach: Spirit, love; new, responsibility.
                                     pain; past, New way of thought.
                                                      Discipline.
  SPECIAL are YOU!
         i am?
Comprehend...
                       hard to.
       Comfort are you in a rocking world, in a storm
          of sin.
                    Stability...
                              *mind
                              *soul.
                   For sure.
</pre>


<!-- break -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trail of Blood]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/short-stories/trail-of-blood"/>
    <updated>2011-04-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/short-stories/trail-of-blood</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The young appearing warrior elf moved with gentle but fierce and deadly grace. He swooped around to my left and right with his ever-glowing sky blue sword. I swung around to face him at each turn, then suddenly shifted my great sword to my right hand and took an expert chop at the small bright-eyed elf. He jumped over me and with a fleeting glance at my defenseless back, sliced at the belt on my loincloth, which subsequently fell to my knees.</p>

<p>Although I had thought that the elf and I were alone, I heard a gruff snickering coming from behind the bushes and trees surrounding us. I tried to look and see where exactly the laughter might be coming from but the elf and my loincloth took up most of my attention. It was sort of drafty without my loincloth and the hysterical elf made matters worse, so I bent over to pick it up when I was suddenly pounced upon from behind by strong but short beings; dwarves. I hate dwarves. Probably more than this elf, my he burn in the underworld. Before I could get the creatures off my back, I was covered with a thick black net and being wrapped up tight, was rendered helpless though I struggled with my sword. My left hand was still stuck somewhere in the vicinity of my knee.</p>

<p>The elf was still laughing and finally managed to get himself under control as he said something to the dwarves in a strange tongue. Though I didn&#8217;t understand the language, I knew and elf sneer when I heard one. I couldn&#8217;t see through the thick netting, but I felt myself being lifted up and carried for a distance before being thrown down. Then we started moving.</p>

<p>It was a long and bumpy trip, and many hours later until we stopped, with no rest upon the way. I was really starting to cramp in my position when the dwarves hands suddenly shot through the net and tied my hands and feet together. I managed to bite one of their fingers off before they got my hands tied though. Blood spurted all over me and the offended dwarf cursed aloud and kicked me repeated in the head. Then the net was lifted and I finally saw some sky blue light through my now blackened eyes. The light was strange, surrounding me though I couldn&#8217;t tell the source. Sitting there on the wagon, observing my surroundings, the only thing I could see was a blue void all around me. No trees. No ground. No dwarves or elf. Nothing but blue and the wagon I sat upon.</p>

<p>I knew the wagon had to be sitting on something, so I wiggled myself around to ask the elf, or perhaps the dwarves, but they were simply gone, nowhere to be found! Where could they have gone? Why would they have taken me here and tied me only to leave me. Then, I saw it. A trail of blood leading away from the wagon. How had I missed that? It must have been from the dwarf whose finger I had tasted. My hands and feet were still tied, so I couldn&#8217;t just run after them. Though, something was poking me in the back. I turned to find a nail sticking from the wagon. The means of my escape!</p>

<p>I wiggling around a bit, putting myself into position until I could get my hands near it the nail and sawed with it for what seemed like hours before the ropes finally frayed enough to give way to my strength. With my hands now free I looked around for my sword, but it was nowhere to be found. I couldn&#8217;t just follow these mad creatures off into an unknown landscape without some sort of weapon, so I ripped one of the larger planks off the wagon and tore at the end until I had fashioned a splinter big enough to impale a small dragon.</p>

<p>With my little wooden spear in in hand, sweat and blood upon my brow, and no minor headache from the blows to my face, I jumped from the wagon to follow the trail of blood, hoping that whatever held up the wagon was going to hold me as well. I had not even taken three steps when I looked back and found the wagon had disappeared into the cold blue haze. I stood there, alone and bloody, spear in hand, encompassed by blue and nothing else to see but this small trail of blood.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Draken's battle]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/short-stories/drakens-battle"/>
    <updated>2011-04-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/short-stories/drakens-battle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Darkness quivered in the back of Draken&#8217;s mind, threatening to disperse his current spell, still held in his commanding thoughts. He could feel the attack coming before it hit and struggled to get enough mana harnessed in order cast the protective one that he now held in preparation.</p>

<p>&#8220;Just a little more&#8221;, he thought to himself. Then just as the darkness was about to overwhelm him, he case his spell, feeling forces gather around him and cling to his mind, shielding it. A sharp gong sounded as his head reeled from the mental force of the impact from the blast he had just barely been able to sheild himself from.</p>

<p>Rubbing his cambrinth ring, shaped as a scorpion, he began to draw mana from it&#8217;s reserves as as the diminishing resources around himself. The darkness, still oozing the in the back of his mind, grew as he added mana to it. Draken had been saving this spell for just such a battle and planned ot use it to it&#8217;s fullest deadly potential this time. He&#8217;d used it in experimentation before, against the likes of wood trolls and creepers, but never to a lethal extent.</p>

<p>&#8220;Now would be the time&#8221;, thought Draken. For his foe was indeed powerful, maybe more powerful than himself, and he hated anything that was more powerful and destroyed those that were with trickery and deceit. With this newly learned spell, he didn&#8217;t exactly need to be more powerful or more learned than his adversary. He just needed the right opening.</p>

<p>Draken saw such an opening as his opponent closed it&#8217;s eyes for just a second.  Mana started flowing toward his foe and Draken knew what was coming.</p>

<p>&#8220;Just a little&#8230;&#8221;, he took a breath through clenched teeth, &#8220;&#8230; more&#8221;. Draken could feel the other almost at it&#8217;s fullest and held that darkness in the back of his mind in check, ready to be unleashed. The other reached his maximum harness and just before the cast, Draken released the darkness from his mind, quickly slipping it past his enemy&#8217;s defenses. His opponent gasped and his eyes flared open in shock. It&#8217;s arms straightened and went rigid, fingers flexed. Shadows began to form around Draken&#8217;s feet and flew to his opponent and down his throat. More shadows seemed to materialize from nowhere and stream into every opening of his foe&#8217;s body, filling him like a balloon.</p>

<p>Standing there bloated and so fat it couldn&#8217;t move or even fall over, the shadows stopped and it&#8217;s mouth closed and opened like a fish as it&#8217;s eyes bulged. It&#8217;s skin crawled with the shadows as they seemed to move just beneath. Tears streamed down it&#8217;s fattened face.</p>

<p>Draken strode over to the bloated live thing and flicked his nose. He laughed a little chuckle to himself, pleased at the outcome of his new spell. It had succeeded in a most pleasing manner, using the victims own mana stores against itself to complete the effects. Helpless now, Draken&#8217;s foe stood where he was, tears still streaming. Darken pulled skinning knife from his belt and waved in it from the the bloated thing. His enemy watched every move of the knife, eyes moving back and forth, in shameless fear and not a small hint of anger. Draken took the knife and pressed the top to the thing&#8217;s nose, wiggling it&#8217;s nose just a little. With a smile, Draken sliced the nose down the middle and the shadows started pouring out of the wound, ripping the flesh bigger and bigger. The shadows poured forth which such force, the creature was ripped apart in a matter of seconds, the shadows disappearing as quickly as they had come.</p>

<p>Draken chuckled to himself once more, wiped the blood spatters from his face and walk on down the trail.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creation]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/short-stories"/>
    <updated>2011-04-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/creation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here is a collection from my younger days. Without code to write, I wrote stories instead, sometimes poetry, and I loved to draw. I&#8217;m still a firm believer that stories and words can program a mind, and in many ways are much more valuable than programming a computer. I also hope that by writing down more of my old material here, it will re-awaken some of those distant chords. I&#8217;ll probably revise some of these as I go as well, I can&#8217;t help refactoring it seems.</p>

<p>I also have no copyright on these.  I would ask that you credit me if you use them, but if you don&#8217;t I&#8217;m not going to sue anyone. It&#8217;s probably not good enough for re-use anyway. ;) Most of them are scenes and not complete stories anyway.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another time, another place...]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/content/another-time-another-place"/>
    <updated>2010-09-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/content/another-time-another-place</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jenney and I moved from Austin to Carolina Beach, North Carolina and the past three.5 months have been amazing! It&#8217;s been like a working vacation. We were right on the beach, with beautiful views, and a personal walkway to the beach which was in a premo-spot. Not a ton of people, lots of waves, and lots of sunshine. We both worked hard, and played hard. It was great and I can honestly say I&#8217;ve lived my &#8216;beach life&#8217; dream for at least a while. Chalk another dream up to &#8216;accomplished&#8217;!</p>

<p>Today marks the start of ANOTHER adventure. We packed up our life once more and left beautiful Carolina Beach behind. Tonight we wait at Jenney&#8217;s best friend&#8217;s (and Maid of Honor&#8217;s) house before our flight tomorrow for San Diego where we will be for a week, staying at her mother&#8217;s house before we are wed on Saturday, September 25th. We&#8217;re both so so so excited to see our friends and family and to celebrate what we&#8217;ve held true in our hearts for the last year; our commitment and love for each other.</p>

<p>After the wedding we&#8217;ll be flying back to North Carolina to pick up our belonging and drive to Colorado Springs where we will continue our life together. Jenney took the opportunity for a Pediatric job in her field of Occupational Therapy and will be doing more of what she loves. She went to school specifically for pediatrics, but the job market has, until now, dictate she work in Geriatrics instead. As you can imagine, the field of Geriatrics is a bit more sobering than getting to play with children all day, which is part of what she&#8217;ll be able to do at her new job. The new job is not quite as lucrative as a traveling position, but we will still be doing fine and loving our life.</p>

<p>My past year with Jenney has been the best year of my life, and I&#8217;m so looking forward to many, many more with her by my side. &#8211; guess I better write my vows ;)</p>

<p>For some of the great pictures we took on our travel this far, check out our photostreams on Flickr.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/43114238@N03/">Jenney&#8217;s Photostream</a>
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sirkitree/">Jerad&#8217;s Photostream</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vampire dream]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/content/vampire-dream"/>
    <updated>2010-01-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/content/vampire-dream</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had a pretty in depth adventure in my dreams last night so I downloaded <a href="http://www.ommwriter.com/en/">ommwriter</a> to capture them in the wee morning hours as soon as I awoke. Ommwriter is pretty nice, the music and the interface really helped for this kind of writing and I think would inspire me to write more poetry. I&#8217;m still listening to the music as I type this up in my blog. Anyway, here are some notes on the things I remember from the dream. Should turn this into a short story.</p>

<ul>
<li>start out searching for lost people down a dark hallway</li>
<li>hole in the wall</li>
<li>go through to find a vampire playing pool, trying to make crazy shots, like off the table, off the wall</li>
<li>knock off the cue ball from a precarious position</li>
<li>pisses off the vampire and I run</li>
<li>fall down a story, over a banister, into a pool of water</li>
<li>notice the missing childrens possessions</li>
<li>notice the missing children, wrapped up in cacoons made of the green weeds lining the bottom of the pool</li>
<li>pull some of the cacoons to the surface</li>
<li>free the children</li>
<li>vampire comes and i set her on fire, first her hair, then with gasoline</li>
<li>throw more gasoline up the stairway and onto her brothers</li>
<li>light the trail and run</li>
<li>i am vampire</li>
<li>they search for me</li>
<li>they find me, and we run from the mother, scatter</li>
<li>i am alone, running through backyards, pissed</li>
<li>there is a pool made of runoff, collected rain in a tarp, redneck pool, in which a male and female human lounge</li>
<li>i am pissed, redneck floating is pissed i&#8217;m in his pool making waves</li>
<li>i jump out, apologise, he threatens me</li>
<li>i am pissed so i tell him to hit me with whatever he has, a couple huge bottles</li>
<li>i warn him i may have some vampiric blood in me and need to feed afterwards</li>
<li>he doesn&#8217;t really understand what i&#8217;ve said and is rearing to hit me anyway</li>
<li>my brother appears, a werewolf and hairy, fangs bared</li>
<li>he bites into the male human and the woman turns to scream</li>
<li>i catch her and make he look into my eyes</li>
<li>draw her mind into mine and tell her all is well</li>
<li>remember well looking into her eyes, connecting with her mind, how it felt to draw her in, how she looked as i became her world, how it felt to have control</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trip to Austin]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/content/trip-austin"/>
    <updated>2009-12-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/content/trip-to-austin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What an adventure! <a href="http://jenneymarie.net">Jenney</a> got a contract in Austin Texas for her next position doing traveling Occupational Therapy, so we packed up the new Subaru Forester (new to us) and started the long trek from Grand Junction, Colorado to Austin, Texas.</p>

<p>Now it hadn&#8217;t snowed much at all in Colorado while we were there, but wouldn&#8217;t it so happen that the day we decide to leave, a huge storm is forecasted to come through! So we set out as early Monday morning as we could (still had a little cleaning to do) and started on our way. It was too far outside of GJ that it started to flurry, and before we arrived in Ouray, we had passed through some areas with some pretty substantial snowfall. But Ouray there was not much of anything on the ground, and the highway pass through the Redridge Mountains was not closed. So even though there was a sign that commercial vehicles were required to have chains, we went against our better judgement and started up the mountain pass instead of staying in Ouray, at the hotspring hotel, like we should have.</p>

<p>The mountains were amazing! Sheer cliff walls and narrow roads all covered in freshly fallen snow&#8230; and it kept getting deeper the higher we went. We were listening to the Lord of the Rings soundtrack on our way up, but when I went around a bend and the back of the car slid just the slightest bit, we turned off the majestic but suspenseful music.</p>

<p>We continued up the mountain pass at a whopping 15MPH and when we came to Silverton we decided to keep going. There were some plows on the road, and there were other vehicles traveling, so we thought we could chance it. We made it <em>almost</em> to Durango when I made a slip in judgement, and was going 20MPH instead of 15MPH coming up on a turn, and the vehicle started to slide as I applied the brakes. We slid off the road, still going quite slow, and took out the front passenger side headlight on a tree. The car bounced to the left and the back end of the car then hit the same spot taking out some of the plastic of the rear brake light and bending up my rear bike wheel which was hitched to the bike rack on the back of the car.</p>

<p>The car stalled, I cursed and pounded the steering wheel, Jenney remained quiet.</p>

<p>I got out of the car to inspect the damage, bent the front side panel back down into place, and got back in the car, kicking the snow from my feet. the car took a couple tries to start, but the engine sounded fine. The damage was completely superficial and since we had all wheel drive, the Subaru pulled right out of the snow bank.</p>

<p>We headed the rest of the way to Durango barely going over 15MPH the rest of the way. Talk about trepidation! When we got to Durango, we stopped at a gas station to get some gas, and I asked the cashier if she had heard the forecast. She said they were due to have about 13inches. I asked if there was a way out of Durango that did not involve mountains. She said she didn&#8217;t know of any. So we drove around town a little while and decided to bunker down at the Adobe hotel, which offerred us an &#8216;early snow rate&#8217; of $40/night.</p>

<p>While we were settling in there, Jenney checked her messages and called back her recruiter who informed her that her contract in Austin had been cancelled! Talk about a depressing day. Stressful snowstorm trek through the precarious mountain pass, damage to our new car, stuck in a snow storm in a town we had not planned on being in and new next to nothing about, and now we were on our way to a job that did not exists.</p>

<p>We stayed in Durango for two nights and checked out the town. Walking through the snow was an adventure for Jenney. Coming from San Diego and being a Cali girl most of her life, she had never experienced a foot of snow before and it was very endearing how her face would light up and she made a snow ball, or a little snow man, or fell backwards in the snow to make a snow angel. She also found that it took a bit of skill to actually <em>walk</em> in the snow ;)</p>

<p>On Wednesday the sun came out and we decided to try our luck getting the heck out of Dodge&#8230; err.. Durango. What we found was that the roads weren&#8217;t so bad and the mountains were no where near as bad as the ones we had come in through, so we probably could have pushed through. But, better safe then sorry - and we didn&#8217;t want to push our luck any more than we already had. So we are glad we waited.</p>

<p>We made it so Santa Fe, New Mexico and decided to stay there for the evening. We still had a headlight out (garages in Durango didn&#8217;t have the parts available) so we decided no driving at night. We found a wonderful bed and breakfast on Manhattan St. and after getting settled, wandered around town for a while. Nice town, found some good beer, but the highlight was the fireplace and bed at the bed and breakfast. We awoke the next morning so refreshed and much less stressed from the ordeal through the mountains and Durango.</p>

<p>We headed out around 9am, after breakfast, and got all the way to Post, Texas where we decided on another bed and breakfast. It was only a fraction more than a local chain motel and much cleaner and homey. It was a historical building and I cold work in comfort and we slept quite well.</p>

<p>In the morning we got up early and were on the road by 7:30am, making it to Austin by about 1:30pm. We found a hotel as our basecamp to start the apartment hunt and after two days of exploring Austin and searching for temporary housing, we&#8217;re now staying in some guy&#8217;s camper that he keeps in his driveway. It&#8217;s clean, safe, and cheap. A much cheaper home base for now until we figure out what is going on with Jenney&#8217;s job and where we&#8217;re going to actually be for the next few months.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
