<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: modules | Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/blog/categories/modules/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-30T18:28:32-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey, you gotta start somewhere right?]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/rolechanger"/>
    <updated>2007-02-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/hey-you-gotta-start-somewhere-right</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So my first commit to the Drupal contributions has been made! WooHoo! I partied hard that night :) No, it's really not that big of a deal, but I'm excited as it takes me one step further into Drupal development and being more involved in the Drupal community.</p>

<p>The module is called <a href="http://drupal.org/projects/rolechanger">rolechanger</a>, and came about when there was a need on a new site I'm building for work that needs to have a menu's links change based upon a chosen role. The roles are created in the main Drupal interface and then you tell rolechanger which roles from that list you would like your users to be able to choose from. Nothing really happens once one of those roles is chosen, at least from a traditional programmatic standpoint since I'll be using javascript for the functionality of changing the menu items. The module is somewhat limited in this respect, but I've included a rolechanger.js file in the module's directory for this purpose and anyone can edit this to define what happens on change using drupal's built in jQuery library. It's really more of a widget I suppose, developed for a specific purpose and probably will not have a whole lot of use to anyone other then my current project, but I contributed it anyway just for the purpose of doing so and gaining the experience of committing code through CVS to Drupal's repository. Hey, you gotta start somewhere right?</p>

<p>Update: <a href="http://jeradbitner.com/node/16">Also, see my post on using some jQuery code with this module.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drupal Theme Loader]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/theme-loader"/>
    <updated>2007-02-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/drupal-theme-loader</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've started a project on <a href="drupal.org">drupal.org</a> to contribute a module that will allow loading of new themes into Drupal from a compressed file (zip, gzip) that is either on your local hard drive, or from a web URL (curl support required?). <a href="http://drupal.org/project/theme-loader">View Project on drupal.org</a></p>

<p>It's a basic idea and I'm hoping to get some feedback from the Drupal community on how best to execute this. The idea came about when <a href="http://improving-home.com">a friend of mine</a> mentioned that he had introduced <a href="http://www.commandtoclient.com/">his brother</a> (a Joomla user) to Drupal and got some feedback from him on what he thought Drupal was lacking.</p>

<p>The first thing mentioned was the weight system. Joomla uses a system similar to that which is implemented in the Views module where you can hit and up or down arrow to resort content. I heard mention that <a href="http://drupal.org/node/91039">someone has been working on a module to do sortables</a> with Drupal's new <a href="jQuery.com">jQuery</a> library, but it looks to be a 4.7 implementation so far.</p>

<p>I've not really seen much discussion on drupal.org about a theme installation interface, so I figure since it would help convert users and there is some good interest at least outside the drupal community, it may take some hold.</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong>
Due to more <a href="http://thevineyardvoice.com">commitments</a> then I have time, I've discontinued any work on this module. My regrets.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
