<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ommwriter | Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/blog/categories/ommwriter/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-29T13:32:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vampire dream]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/vampire-dream"/>
    <updated>2010-01-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/vampire-dream</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had a pretty in depth adventure in my dreams last night so I downloaded <a href="http://www.ommwriter.com/en/">ommwriter</a> to capture them in the wee morning hours as soon as I awoke. Ommwriter is pretty nice, the music and the interface really helped for this kind of writing and I think would inspire me to write more poetry. I'm still listening to the music as I type this up in my blog. Anyway, here are some notes on the things I remember from the dream. Should turn this into a short story.</p>

<ul>
<li>start out searching for lost people down a dark hallway</li>
<li>hole in the wall</li>
<li>go through to find a vampire playing pool, trying to make crazy shots, like off the table, off the wall</li>
<li>knock off the cue ball from a precarious position</li>
<li>pisses off the vampire and I run</li>
<li>fall down a story, over a banister, into a pool of water</li>
<li>notice the missing childrens possessions</li>
<li>notice the missing children, wrapped up in cacoons made of the green weeds lining the bottom of the pool</li>
<li>pull some of the cacoons to the surface</li>
<li>free the children</li>
<li>vampire comes and i set her on fire, first her hair, then with gasoline</li>
<li>throw more gasoline up the stairway and onto her brothers</li>
<li>light the trail and run</li>
<li>i am vampire</li>
<li>they search for me</li>
<li>they find me, and we run from the mother, scatter</li>
<li>i am alone, running through backyards, pissed</li>
<li>there is a pool made of runoff, collected rain in a tarp, redneck pool, in which a male and female human lounge</li>
<li>i am pissed, redneck floating is pissed i'm in his pool making waves</li>
<li>i jump out, apologise, he threatens me</li>
<li>i am pissed so i tell him to hit me with whatever he has, a couple huge bottles</li>
<li>i warn him i may have some vampiric blood in me and need to feed afterwards</li>
<li>he doesn't really understand what i've said and is rearing to hit me anyway</li>
<li>my brother appears, a werewolf and hairy, fangs bared</li>
<li>he bites into the male human and the woman turns to scream</li>
<li>i catch her and make he look into my eyes</li>
<li>draw her mind into mine and tell her all is well</li>
<li>remember well looking into her eyes, connecting with her mind, how it felt to draw her in, how she looked as i became her world, how it felt to have control</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
