<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Jerad Bitner</title>
		<description></description>
		<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>eliza and the AI Frontier</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The world of technology never ceases to amaze me with its rapid evolution and unexpected convergences. Recently, I’ve been deeply involved with an exciting project at the intersection of artificial intelligence and cryptocurrency - the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ai16z/eliza&quot;&gt;@ai16z/eliza&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;eliza, named after Joseph Weizenbaum’s groundbreaking 1966 chatbot, is reimagining what’s possible when we combine modern AI capabilities with blockchain technology. This isn’t just another chatbot; it’s a vision of how autonomous AI agents might interact with both humans and the digital economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My journey with eliza began with the fundamental building blocks - setting up the project infrastructure that would enable our growing community of contributors. I established the initial GitHub project management workflows, implementing project boards and issue templates to streamline our development process. One of my first contributions was setting up the continuous integration pipeline, ensuring that every code contribution maintains our quality standards and can be confidently deployed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started work on expanding eliza’s reach by developing a Slack client, allowing the agent to interact with teams in their native workspace environments. There’s something fascinating about building these bridges between AI agents and human communication platforms - each new integration opens up novel possibilities for interaction and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project has grown to encompass several fascinating repositories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ai16z/eliza&quot;&gt;The core eliza platform&lt;/a&gt; for Twitter and Discord interactions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ai16z/elizas-world&quot;&gt;eliza’s world&lt;/a&gt; - a space where AI swarms come to life&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ai16z/elizas-list&quot;&gt;eliza’s list&lt;/a&gt; - a growing collection of community projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ai16z/eliza-starter&quot;&gt;eliza-starter&lt;/a&gt; - A starter kit for developers looking to build their own AI agents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What excites me most about this project is how it bridges multiple technological paradigms. We’re not just building tools; we’re exploring fundamental questions about AI autonomy, digital identity, and economic interaction in the age of artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crypto aspect adds another fascinating layer. How do autonomous agents interact with digital assets? What does it mean for an AI to have its own wallet, to make transactions, to participate in an economy? These aren’t just theoretical questions anymore - we’re building the infrastructure to answer them practically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reminds me of my earlier work with VR and web technologies. Just as virtual reality opened up new ways of experiencing digital spaces, AI agents are opening up new ways of interacting with digital systems. The difference is that while VR extended human presence into digital spaces, AI agents are creating new forms of digital presence entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, I see enormous potential in this space. We’re not just creating tools for human use; we’re potentially bootstrapping an entire ecosystem of autonomous digital entities that can interact, trade, and evolve in ways we’re only beginning to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The community’s response has been incredible. Developers and creators are already building on top of eliza, extending its capabilities in unexpected directions. It’s reminiscent of the early days of the web, when every new project seemed to open up ten more possibilities. From my vantage point managing our GitHub workflows, I’ve had the privilege of watching new contributors join the ecosystem, each bringing their unique perspective and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What keeps me up at night (in the best way possible) is thinking about the implications. How will these AI agents evolve? What kind of economy will they create? How will they interact with human society? These are the questions that drive our development, and I’m thrilled to be part of finding the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those interested in joining this journey, the project is open source and welcomes contributors. Whether you’re interested in AI, blockchain, or both, there’s something here for you to explore and build upon. Our CI pipeline makes it easy to get started - you can have your first PR merged within hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future is coming faster than we think, and it’s being shaped by projects like eliza. I’m grateful to be part of this revolution, and I can’t wait to see what we’ll build next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S. If you’re interested in getting involved, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ai16z/&quot;&gt;eliza repositories on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. The future is open source, and it needs builders like you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2024/11/eliza-and-the-ai-frontier/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024/11/eliza-and-the-ai-frontier/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Jenney Journal, part 32</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Things have been going really well as Jenney heals at home. She’s back to doing everything she was always able to do, and our latest scans have shown no signs of cancer growth! Praise God!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenney gave her testimony at church today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/krH4g3LK1b4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be taking Jeanne home next weekend to San Diego, and staying with her for a couple of weeks before returning home. It’ll be a long drive with the whole family, and God is with us. The change in weather will be a welcome respite from the cold, wet winter here. But I am excited for the beauty of spring in Washington!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2021/01/jenney-journal-32/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/01/jenney-journal-32/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Candala</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/TrO6c01iA9BqHdFiyg8DzlIJRJSQi5hQxk7cpqKaHjY7E0XPYYy6DxfJS9Ucwcs55GvDQDxqU2F3ArLurQASUR5qK9DjEApDpSopFWmUBqxj5wfxm6u1QmU7FqpmuNqUtx_NciJhbnDNYnkmzAf51yXJTjL21F9l93O9dZ9l9spyiFue-9fdZ254N5C0iSqzZcr2Ytej3_Fy_p58XfdA4zdEJUYSdM1hryRCrFHdJIzn5kpH5y4bPgoZBHdOh1aempxOST5RjATxqj-f_15wIGJrWvL4C7re085zx12G54h_9XRsWmIEqBhDxzZdcA9zW_C0dyTfnlSrzhpwughxNm0U544_L5ODLHQygrwcCnJJYgkg7kjYjJd-56Q4Dg_prHVLRQ87qS2eqiCk91vQOSS5eMfimZ5uRBnQkyvtjl55RoW0uKR-IR-kJRAJ8IXKCWVS3tdqSLzJOiwROPb7CtOLIbnEx1lr6AN6nSqey8NIaM3dJavoqEo44aNyrA8gg18bMFEgKQthRcbvTqoA-nuRxZKfng00lJUFpv5gDCshUwuvsBEVsHM81EeXlBjHh8pMViXaCjoYuMT2M9mx4fYe3lTacE3JQkqhUyjUKanRP8vb9_TJFICZi9pWeJF1TrflgPBy7Yqf8e0hzSSP3az3s5vqNhDJ01ua2rTovp-J8teMwnRhtu0tmCDEIz9ishIUTRGQ4OZ-AavJ2s_CwKZSSWGjBTKLHQP0u_admsJ6-Hudp_kzbKvJ=w1440-h810-no?authuser=0&quot; atl=&quot;At the end of February 2020, my wife underwent surgery to remove a metastatic melanoma tumor from her brain. She has made a full recovery from the surgery, but our fight with cancer is just starting. &quot; style=&quot;width:100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/BHBpCCIIZRhb6sGoe-L1rn7AMtHLdYsJJrbVC_OmYKHR0yeCqxzSjWOVLpqLbnbbwXlEBMFlj71zB9Op6G7G3fzmB8EgxCSEqv20c1GZ4HiHEVuTacGf_zuiolvNeEOz7PBv7j2veh0Yku6YIN44MT0bZRTVjOTDhOT3HZyZ_7TyQUWP6AEi3gcjy7NSVhYE5kJAaKMdDMONdsNpjCF_PFHDZen6GmPXHOfmlNGnSd3w3ey5_jf0KHkNZd74vzxYLCt8MgbwG0MdE_JRwOpk4Yq1bYeByrLsbGsOZVpFXtkVD8EYb4iI66Ykh9-5ceoeShOAvwuiFip8rjc9L5a6hTIbmRYmuN5WmNWxjbJGyxPbt_fxwQlUq-9KeZBEjbN8LvefnmCsCoGQtJI3Wpg0wNM8vaK529QaKYvWzU4dNjJRC3CqkDuQR6eXK1oOEULfzCJCY8uAmB-jxvA-y0Srg0-GeMo5b8NXxWZVrbFgoEPemOdom4262x2_a8iUCWZK4WZS7JdG2F1vo6dWo0ZAEltW8QDjFOllxONnPC9U65K3aLeBILNRu_bt23qokt2XUPO6pR8rHqPS2gzRJH0hSljh4GjGExcaUNOhwd7hP0xHl13w4g8pKq79BXZRO28NDPQEhAb1gRqTPypPs75DriV38Ky9DmGkw_gxlxpWtBKP5cgMydvQY8neHr-pGcy3F2SpCfXWqw3pYF1LojfB61i0WIvJhoIyOl7zKiECPSpfcTYs017bWgHu=w972-h548-no?authuser=0&quot; style=&quot;float:left; width:50%; height:50%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/NMHVgmc6wCEsZWriO239vuBhIIt_iikTpO8WP2sfklh4w6RK5K_msW5UzYgRUq5gjZRAgSmA0DRpd1tIXh5tedXl6-PyQw4e8t7QOp5z1BVTSNgM-b3GIWED3rDC-3FIm1VJTakCRLXEVEOjFoAveeqn67XMe1UCtWMc-a803UYi_7OXDl4esVxC9GvB9_2b6VAWOTG2rQcPSJvGw4HL9bevGfmF7PwdKKnQwhMKhLhnRtI0mhDWdNUW7HRLJddDaCqAfbDOz-NGmYfkBp0v39g8ASYiW_JY0_vAJK6uYEgN-nNMvLgbq06zk_tNGdpYTyKj8qyzJZ0yKw__EaGRET-uyJGFmY0iuY6CH0QgXKi9nFVyRCXf7kqIzyLmuLTAEYRnJMvoux5Wy_2HTFfgzQoMOyz1riD6rVzqUD_XsfVluU9piQJgQ-4B6_TpBlA4a_41DvIB5PdlILmLrObTnBkt0Cfi0tQj7NpGhDod_q-M-hpCv5Lipv13Gi1ogi-y423NGkYVnaBUUOz3fDxhq_yGm0j6Tr6NikRqaphoV71yqCWjH2m2uvfrANbf_SqB6ziIbYyfweKiFN3wo58mUgF9TJyPTvU2cmq3l1pfpS5sDIcNEYjQNOXxzJrZ-UmzUEnUFo99fPTQXQLtfBXUJtR4UypfK7jJJbpZ2GD_WWW3YuaU7cGdUki5gdRYmXWHD_Lv1m7j0uOIdRUuqvM36stTvVO9OaWIE4epNa5SGpgx6JMD3ELpRhSM=w808-h456-no?authuser=0&quot; style=&quot;width:50%; height:50%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/G1RTr3_v7f_DExPBCMNFEwLC7dQEOZ1HiUppAQFTf_lYmiG2bFO4GvB7m9d0mxccmMpI1zFwdtEz0oXPHX9QgzjC8wByL75cdgjcFqrcHAjS4hEcOSxFGXL5QLxc09xr8ynEJZBfnrh-dZ6T2JdJfpX1CZkazwZwPn-f3Qb8cGOfyyH2tq2LCoZodunR6SP8Ji45_e8r3d5tmfqndCEquKIP3WFYCmapAKlWm_IG9ql2sxSXhaA2LoVBAuRpW2QUBBoO62Xu8SiIEXgdYW9q1wHUmutF9753PhXjg2uECkIOmV6sXVoSk1j1TuhUgVSgv2kyGmNENGd13Gp92EKHGzvA_X3jaFt00TRfENFVXbEYFgVHrvw_arU71o4iStFJGF685NvZyjPxDNfM8XZpBXmGznMmb2-LR_xMJRjT7NJksv2HCli7IHzLKIoRCbKVBToyMIA7jqYIywiOY6yQrQcqar_sywoUqpnQADvkaTolUUIOx0XNtFqZTR1-GbRzm3mNHi2NIRIS8PXEakRcdwl-AACdo0_lukzucKU2n4xcsN4qnJB9sILhLxhUrkXDeIfwiwmqMGyfnzMC4FUlzNgMmKlcwv07yr1ZySxk0D9B97YgTMgCEhcmAm3mLDALRzXTtWxaPFTn0MWJkQIl2aAtPRoERU_PVj6PnAExUCaX4QJu5RuE-JukfWgEEGQ96exgQdwd0Z59J3Q87VsCiJdvbSfSTH-mSEk5BFVGLgYDWNp79h5BjHky=w960-h540-no?authuser=0&quot; style=&quot;width:100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/candala/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/11/candala/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Jenney Journal, part 31</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;On Oct 21, Jenney started to get nauseous and diarrhea. She became very dehydrated quickly, and had a seizure. I called our oncologist who said we should call 911 and get her into the ER. We spent the day in the ER where they ran various tests and could find no real cause for the seizure. They started her on Kepra and sent us home. The diarrhea continued. Imodium had no effect. Stronger medications had no effect. I had to take her in every other day to get an IV for fluids, and her potassium keeps getting low. Finally, a week after having constant diarrhea (10-20 times per day) the oncologist said she needed to be admitted to the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;St. Joseph’s was full. St. Anthony’s was full. They finally found a bed for her at St. Clare. When we got there they already had a room for her, but it wasn’t clean. We sat and waited for a while and I talked to the admissions clerk. He said he’s never seen the hospitals so full, and that it was definitely covid, though most folks have it a few days and it’s like the flu and then goes away. And none of the staff has been getting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenney has been beside herself in the hospital. She’s alone, lonely, and confused a lot because she’s on some very strong drugs again. They ran tons of tests and have only recently landed on it being another immune response due to the immunotherapy medications. “Immune mediated enteritus, caused by Optivo”. This time her white blood cells are attacking her small intestines, inflaming them and making them not work, they can’t absorb nutrient and liquids from what she eats. And it’s painful, not all the time, but the cramping that happens with digestion is really bad for her. And it’s been over two weeks now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I talked to her today, she had only gone about 4 times, and her potassium level was up high enough. I’m still not sure they’ll send her home or not until the diarrhea stops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if all that isn’t enough, today I noticed Sebastian’s neck swelling again. Two years ago the lymph nodes in his neck became infected with a bacteria and they had to be surgically removed. He had two operations as they didn’t get it all the first time. Is this a recurrence? I pray it is not. Funny how even that seems almost like a small thing by comparison to the rest of this year. I’ll get him a pediatric appointment this week to see what they say. Hopefully it’s just a sore throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcus had his 6 month child wellness checkup this week. He’s doing great. A little small, but that’s to be expected for a premie. He’s teething, which brings it’s own challenges. Thankfully Jeanne, Jenney’s mom has been here these last few weeks to help me with the kids. I couldn’t work and do all the running between the grocery store, hospitals, and school for lunches. I’m also thankful that some folks from church and neighbors have brought us some meals and learning materials for the kids. It means a lot when someone stops by with something and we can talk a little, asking about jenney and the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part my anxiety around everything has been under control. But not all the time. I know through everything that God has a plan, that I have a role in that plan, and I will play it out day by day as he gives me strength to do so. I also get a lot of strength from my children. They are so well behaved, they love to learn, and they all play so well together. Marcus’ laugh is the brightest, most beautiful sound to my ears and never fails to bring me joy. :) I see God through my children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/jenney-journal-31/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/11/jenney-journal-31/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sadness</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/FZd8RxE9LXfAgQnQjOH_Yca84IDTJVazCY4oxZ8EmbjSK_OIuMiyRLsthnArA1AIImyVmPPZXcKGSt38a6W7Wa-QuljMeTgXV5KJeP1l9GWszpLw5FHebpvCXJDYA9Fv6VkXIy90snx6YnxilVm1Fs3yIAONvYe4xuA24KvEoGVb8KxFcK7IStdVwqDPY_Invzn8l7ISX_Fquf9oBmUZ96GESMFCzrBxfhSPTU9DezgDIgstHjFa6rKuPfg4-lccE0RiqPEQ3o_gf6kfEujfMSDivptKb2MWZJQ8iY8DKt5A3CPEGkTW8wD9wirlmypVndsj-EhkOoaNZbkJNR4fp2Np3rcxiZdzEgVb_aUp_tQRP2YXCqhzXpojLtrjOWLYqBzc9O50wZ4cVpObSv10EZ55Xsymy9agzXTYNMQGSGR4hUdx7XLDpWyTpGQSsNY--AtvQVpDC7gxVhgNmf880j0qFlMvOGcz-ctXuwDNJ7jXf4ttisfsa2QJV02rP-pFzpD17WNOaYuUEivkG7Kft-zvWEPn1NycQi3VlkrS5r2JkitPZUyFsjVtle7urmptJt6jHerfhll3I9LGVacxHp_yuiSKAEv0-W-BDlcnV_CZl7K9LclsGIWB-dus6QBnToYhslzmhO36KiDv0sL5k5q_R6l0rcIOIWfGVJBDMEKgxzYhVF91S9SIVEgZWlOI7SnIPdhM52Ejw986cQZrjuV7J6KGysCC5OSpGmDXu9V38_LClzuJWpQ=w872-h756-no?authuser=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/sadness/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/11/sadness/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Jenney Journal, part 30</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Jenney was diagnosed in February of 2020 with stage 4 metastatic melanoma which had spread to her brain. The survival rate of stage 4 metastatic melanoma is about 25%. After 2 brain surgeries, a C-section operation to deliver our son Marcus, an extensive recovery from encephalitis caused by the immune therapy, and hives from a reaction to an antibiotic… there are now no signs of the cancer. We had a Pet scan and an MRI of her brain and they found no signs of the cancer or growth. The visible lumps under her skin in 5 different places are gone. The spot on her lung is gone. The spots in her brain are gone. There is still scar tissue from the surgeries in her brain but they show no signs of growth. 9 months after what could have been a death sentence, Jenney is healed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This miracle did not come cheaply. So many friends and family have prayed and petitioned our Lord and savior Jesus Christ. They’ve supported us through gifts, cards, prayers, encouragement, time, and love. Thank you. Know that your thoughts and prayers did not go unanswered. Know that God is good, He is real, and He listens to our prayers. We’ve struggled so hard to find and hold onto what little faith we could find, and the Lord heard our prayers. Thank you Jesus, for working through the doctors, through Jim Allison who discovered immunotherapy, and through our church; the body of Christ. I will spend the rest of my life thanking Him, praising Him, and finding ways to serve Him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenney is still on a fairly high dose of steroids currently, an antibiotic, an antiviral, and antacid - all preventative measures. The steroid causes acid buildup, and lowers white blood cell count, which is what counteracts her amped up white blood cells from attacking her brain again. This does however cause the jitters, and confusion making it hard to think at times. But we’re lowering the dose by about 2mg per week right now and at that rate she should only have to take them another month at the most. We’re hopeful we can lower the dosage quicker soon and be off of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many miracles this year. Coming out of the first brain surgery. Having Marcus. Recovering from the second brain surgery. Recovering from the encephalitis. Recovering from stage 4 cancer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in awe of our God, the God of Abraham, Issac, and Jacob. We’re getting to know Him much better in our household, by reading the Bible almost every day to our children, by having consistent quiet time with Him, and by watching renditions of the Gospels on Amazon Prime Video. I’m currently going through Matthew, and reading “Knowing God”. I thank God every morning when I wake up next to Jenney and try to keep Him with me all day, as I work, as I teach my children, praying with my family at meals and before bed time. We’re instilling rituals into our daily lives that incorporate learning about Him and making Him a part of everything we can. I’m hoping to start serving more in our church by lending my time and technical talents in various ways. I’ve joined a small group and hope to help with family ministries as well. I’m learning more about giving and living for God, and not just my career any longer. I’m learning to ask God where He wants me to go, and what He wants me to do, and not just doing what I want. I’m excited for the future and what it may hold for me, my family, my friends, and my community. Here I am Lord, where do you want me to go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also started seeing a therapist. There is a lot of processing I need to do around the events of this year. So far it’s been good in that I can share things with my therapist in a way that I cannot with others, and receive some tools for handling myself in healthier ways. It’s good to have help in this area. Improving my mental health will help those around me as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/jenney-journal-30/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/10/jenney-journal-30/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Jenney Journal, part 29</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a full three weeks since I last wrote. In that time Jenney was&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in the hospital for a total of 10 days,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;returned home on the 21st,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;spent time recovering at home,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;developed insomnia; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;had an alergic reaction to one of her medications resulting in hives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly after I published my last blog post about Jenney, I went to visit her at the hospital. As you might guess I was slightly dreading that she would be even worse and during the car ride went from dread to acceptance. By the time I arrived at the hospital peace had settled in on me and I went through the covid checkpoint calmly. As I walked down the hallway of the hospital, I suddenly had a clear vision of Jenney sitting up in bed, eating breakfast, and smiling at me as I walked through the door. Encouraged, I rode the elevator up to her floor. When I arrived at her room, this exact vision is what greeted me, and I broke down and wept as I held her hand, putting it to my face and thanking God. She was confused by my reaction and asked me what was the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Couldn’t you find me?” she asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, no dear. I couldn’t find you at all,” I finally replied after trying to explain just how bad she had been. She didn’t remember it at all. But she was eating a good breakfast, and smiling at me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next week brought more IV’s of anitbiotics, antivirals, and some good days, some bad. Jenney went up and down in terms of lucidity and responsiveness, but throughout it all I held on to that premonition. God had shown me that even in my darkest hours He is there, working to heal Jenney, to encourage us, and it reminds me to not doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That day I we also met a neurologist who wanted to do a bedside LP to get more spinal fluid. Long story-short: he botched it and Jenney has multiple puncture wounds and bruises from his botched attempts. He eventually gave up and ordered it done on Monday under xray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In talking to the medical doctor the next day, she reported that Jenney was anemic, iron deficient, and was still on antibiotics and antivirals even though they had determined that the infection was not bacterial in nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8/17/2020&lt;/strong&gt;
Not a great day. Jenney’s speech aphasia was worse this day, she had a headache, and while she was very hot, did not have a fever. Tylenol seemed to help and we saw some more doctors. But mostly at this poitn we were just waiting for Monday to get the spinal tap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we did at least have a report that it was not HSV… but they kept her on antibiotics and antivirals still…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8/19/2020&lt;/strong&gt;
Jenney’s oxygen was low. The doctor mentioned that her bed stay had resulted in her having partially collapsed lungs so they put her on oxygen and told her to practice filling her lungs consciously which she was mostly able to remember to do on her own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave her a shower that day, and tried my best to brush out the tangled mess her hair had become. I should have remembered that her hair would get like that and put it up when we first entered the hospital… but I did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A physical therapist came that day to do an eval, and we walked around the floor with a walker and an oxygen tank in tow. Jenney did well and half way through stopped using the walker. She was unsteady, but did not fall on the way back to her room. She was still in pretty good spirits, but very tired. I’d leave when she needed a nap to go home and be with the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8/20/2020&lt;/strong&gt;
They took her back off of oxygen, but were monitoring her heart rate now more closely. It had gotten very high for no apparent reason a few times and they put her on a beta blocker for that. So many meds…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8/21/2020&lt;/strong&gt;
They decided that she was recovering fairly well and decided to allow her to come home, knowing she had help. She still needed help to the bathroom, walking, and remembering, but was very ready to get home and be with the kids. I went into the hospital that day with clothes, watched them pull out the tube they had run to her heart that her IV’s go into (holy cow that was a long tube), cleaned her up after she didn’t make it to the toilet, helped her dress, and went to get the van while they wheeled her down in a chair to go home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We celebrated that night with steak, shrinmp, corn on the cob, and grilled zuccini from our garden. Jenney fell asleep before dinner, but we saved her some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s now two weeks later, and Jenney’s recovery from this episode has taken longer than the first two surgeries. We’re trying to be patient, and we’re seeing progress with her energy levels, her aphasia, and her strength. ANd just when she was really starting to feel like herself again, the hives started. We’ve since discontinued the medication that the doctor thinks caused it, but it’s still itchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenney still get’s confused, especially at night and in the morning, mostly not trusting her memories, not knowing if they actually happened. One night in particular during a bout with insomnia she started thinking she was Korra, from a cartoon we watch with the kids. I convinced her the next morning she was in fact Jenney by asking her about our family, their names, their birthdays, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hives and insomnia are the biggest challenges right now, because of the confusion the insomnia causes, the irritability of the iteching, and in general, feeling like getting kicked when you’re down. It’s demoralizing and we’re doing our best to keep her spirits up. She exercises, we go for walks with the kids, have dinner on the lawn in this wonderful weather we’re having. We find moments of joy, and continue to have faith and thank God for healing her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have a road ahead of us, and we’ll have good days and bad, but overall we try to remain hopeful and patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if that all isn’t enough, we’ve also decided to homeschool the children this year. 3+ hours of Zoom per day for kids simply isn’t something I want to subject them to. I think I can handle the schooling after work with help from many folks who have given us guidance and advice. I have ordered curriculum for Vincent and Viola and am going over that and teacher guides for the material with some anticipation of starting next week. Jenney will take on teaching Sebastian his numbers, letters, shapes, colors, and learning how to read. Wish us luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/jenney-journal-29/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/09/jenney-journal-29/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Jenney Journal, part 28</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I believe that Jenney will be healed, fully and completely, and by the grace of God will see her children grow and meet her grandchildren.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But let him ask in faith without any doubting, for the one who doubts is like the surf of the sea driven and tossed by the wind.” - James 1:6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m doing my best to not feel driven and tossed by the wind, to believe without doubting. When I can manage it, I feel peace, and when I cannot, I’m ravaged like the surf in a storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenney has been losing weight over the last month. When she stopped eating everything on her plate at dinner, I started taking note. She said she felt nauseas after eating. After a little while it was after drinking as well. I started tracking how much she ate, encouraging her to drink by making her tea, or finding novel sugar-free beverages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a week ago she started feeling cold, all the time. Jenney had her last double immunotherapy treatment on Friday. The Thursday before, she said she couldn’t get warm. On a warm day we went to her typical neuro post-op and while I wore shorts, she covered up with long pants, long sleeves, and wore a winter coat. She had a slight fever when the nurse checked, and we blew it off a little as during the previous visit to her oncologist, he mentioned that feeling cold was typical. We figured the elevated temp was due to wearing such warm clothes on a hot day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend I started recording her temperatures. She had fevers during the night, chills during the day, and headaches sometimes accompanying the fevers. I consulted with the oncologist who recommended Tylenol every 4 hours, which seemed to help bring her temperature down. She would barely eat, and barely drink. The fever continued, and on Monday, our oncologist asked us to come in to get blood cultures and urinalysis to check for infection. They found nothing. Her fevers continued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8/11/2020&lt;/strong&gt;
On Tuesday around 3 she awoke from a nap and her fever hit 102.5. I took her to the emergency room at the recommendation of her oncologist. They wouldn’t let me wait with her to be admitted, but she could call me once she was admitted. I made sure to iterate that to Jenney, to call me as soon as she went back. I waited in the car for over an hour and finally called to check if she had been admitted. She answered and said she had. I tried to go in but couldn’t get past security as I had forgotten my ID, so drove back home (just 10 minutes away thankfully) got my wallet, and headed back to the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the ER Jenney laid there on the bed, awaiting a doctor or nurse. They wheeled her back to get a CT scan, and a chest x-ray. Then they drew blood again for lab cultures from both arms. Then wanted to do a covid test, but Jenney refused. She’d had two of them previously and really couldn’t tolerate the swab being pushed so far into her nose. The doctor came back to explain that they wanted to do an MRI but had to go through the hospital to do it, and for that she needed a test. She offered Ativan to sedate her, and said she did not have to have the test, and they would still admit her, but she’d need to be quarantined and would not be able to have any visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked how long the results would take and she said about 2 days. “So she won’t be quarantined until the results? She just has to have the test, not a negative result? How does that make any sense?” She couldn’t explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenney agreed to the test so that I’d be able to be with her. Once the Ativan kicked in the nurse came back and said she’d be super quick and very gentle. She’d had the test herself and knew how to do it well. Jenney tolerated it pretty well under the influence of the Ativan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They admitted her to the hospital and I left to go get the kids dinner and help Jeanne get them ready for bed. Jeanne was going to leave just the day before but decided not to since Jenney was having fevers and was in bed all the time. Once the boys were down, I left to go sit with Jenney. Her short term memory was deteriorating, but she was conversing with me at least. They had her on antibiotics and saline with electrolytes and she at least had her appetite back. I fed her some dinner that she ordered from the hospital. That alone felt nice as she hadn’t been able to eat anything other than a little soup and crackers in almost a week now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8/12/2020&lt;/strong&gt;
The results of the x-ray of her chest were clean. There were some markers in her blood though for pneumonia which was why they had her on a general antibiotic IV. They would do the MRI today and I noted that Jenney was having more trouble finding words, and couldn’t remember something we were talking about just 5 or 10 minutes ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited her three times, morning, afternoon, and evening, and each time she was only getting worse. Being 10 minutes away was convenient, but it was still hard to go back and see her worsen each time, and come back home to report to Jeanne that I saw no improvement. I kept texting her oncologist and neurosurgeon to keep them updated with what I saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8/13/2020&lt;/strong&gt;
When I went in to see her in the morning, she recognized me, said she recognized me, but couldn’t tell me my name, nor her own. I fed her breakfast and talked with her nurse. She was extremely tired and kept falling asleep. Around noon the Dr whose care she was under called to say they were going to order a lumbar puncture (spinal tap) to check her spinal fluid for infection. I went in and signed some papers and they did the procedure around 2:45pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admit that at this point I was starting to despair. I kept the words of James in my head, to not doubt. I rebuked the spirits of fear, worry, and doubt out loud in Jesus name. I asked Jesus to guard my heart and guard my mind. I haven’t stopped asking Him multiple times a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8/14/2020&lt;/strong&gt;
I got to the hospital early as Dr Senecal said he would be there around 7am. At 7 they started her IV drips and she immediately starting having a very bad headache, worse than I’d seen since before her first surgery. She laid there cringing and crying and trying to breath as I held her hand and cried with her. They gave her some Tylenol and then wheeled her out to get a CT scan stat. They tried to get her into a wheel chair but couldn’t so wheeled her bed instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Senecal came in around 7:45, took her vitals, and did a nuero test. She was not able to say her name, but was strong and could follow some simple directions. She lifted the wrong leg when asked, but got it after some tries. Dr Senecal called our neurosurgeon Dr Goldman and I listened to them go over possibilities, results from the spinal tap, etc. They had no ideas, but wanted to transfer her over to St Joseph’s in Tacoma where they have more specialists and could access her more easily since they are both based there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Senecal left and came rushing back in about 10 minutes later stating he thought it was encephalitis due to the immunotherapy. He ordered dexamethasone (a steroid she’s been on more than not this year) and left again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They came to transfer her around 4:30pm. At this point she didn’t recognize or acknowledge me, and I lost it. She just looked uncomfortable and upset. I signed the papers to transfer her, gathered her things and headed home again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went over to her room at St Joseph’s around 8pm. Her nurse came in briefly but I visiting hours were over at 9 and I had to leave. I took our calendars again, the ones she’s made over the years with pictures from the year, and placed them around her room then left my contact information and a bunch of notes on the board for her nurse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/jenney-journal-28/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/08/jenney-journal-28/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Jenney Journal, part 27</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This past month has been a blessing. It reminds me of April which was a calm in the eye of the storm as Jenney recovered from her first brain surgery. We knew there would be the other side of the storm to go through, knowing Marcus was going to be born and that we would have to start treatments, but we didn’t know it was going to be so extremely harrowing with the additional brain surgery. But this last half of June and first half of July have been like April, with not only Jenney recovering again, but also with Marcus growing so big and so strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenney has had two systemic treatments for her cancer so far. This consists of two medications that comprise her immunotherapy treatment. Each is intravenous and takes about two hours to administer, every three weeks. This coming Friday is her third treatment. So far the only side effect she’s had has been a pretty intense rash on her arms, legs, and chest. For that they subscribed a steroid cream that has helped. It doesn’t bother her very much other than remembering to apply it twice a day. I’m also happy to say that one of the smaller spots on her back I can’t seem to find any longer. I’m pretty sure I know where it was located, and that it’s simply gone. Some of her other small lumps under her skin also seem to have reduced in size. We haven’t had any official scans on those to measure if they’ve shrunk at all, but we’re pretty sure they have. I’m not sure when they are going to do another PET CT scan to check her body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did have another MRI on July 1st. They were going to wait longer, but I convinced them that since the tumor had grown back last time within 6 weeks, we should do another as soon as we could. The initial results were a bit scary, in that the technician’s report stated that the initial resection spot had increased in size about a centimeter, and the additional spot they’d noticed on the MRI 5 weeks prior to this one had also grown about half a centimeter. However, after our Oncologist, Radio Oncologist, and Neurosurgeon all conferred, they said that this amount of growth at this stage was very insignificant in comparison to how fast it grew last time. Our Oncologist said that he would order a perfusion MRI which will measure blood flow to the sites, and that would better indicate if they were cancerous or not. If they are, we might consider the gamma knife treatment, but at this stage we should be patient and let the immunotherapy do it’s work. They growth may also just be scar tissue growing over those parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waiting is the hardest thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcus is growing like a weed. Monday we had another pediatric check-up and the doctor was very surprised at his growth. 1 month prior Marcus was in the 6th percentile for weight, and now at 8lbs 11oz, he’s in the 41st percentile. He’s also 21 inches tall now which took him from the 9th percentile to the 51st! Having an Italian grandmother who helps us make sure he’s fed is really paying off. :) He’s still eating pretty much every 3 hours, but sometimes stretches it to 4 hours. He’s always very gassy, which seems to pain him a lot, and his belly button also has become herniated. But the doctor (and baby forums) have assured us that this is all normal and each would resolve itself in time. We keep a band aid on his belly button though, just to help keep it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than doctor office visits and grocery store runs, we pretty much keep home. We’ve gone on a few picnics at state parks, and we visit with our few neighbors on our street. Vincent got a chance to go to his friend’s house down the road on Friday, but for the most part we spend our time with the kids, in the garden, and in our yard. The weather here has been beautiful, and the flowers are constantly in bloom and rotating which ones fragrances waft past us while having dinner on the back deck under our little gazebo tent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeanne is still here with us and takes the morning shift around 2 or 3am for feeding Marcus. We did have a short stint without her when she went to visit Jenney’s brother and sister-in-law, Jim and Amanda for a few days. This gave Jenney and me a chance to experience what it would be like staying up with Marcus. It was hard, but I think we have a system that’ll work for when she does decide to go home at the beginning of August. We’ll miss her terribly though. All of our lives are so much better with her here, but she has friends and more family in San Diego to love and spend time with as well. :) Still, it’s never the same when she’s gone, but we’ll be alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we pray, we always add these three things: Thank you God for healing Mommy, for helping Marcus grown big and strong, and for Nonna (grandma in Italian) being here with us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/jenney-journal-27/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/07/jenney-journal-27/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Jenney Journal, part 26</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Looking for words to describe the past couple of weeks; stressful, joyful at times, peaceful, some frustrations, a lot of gratitude. Overall Jenney continues to recover from her second craniotomy remarkably well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not been without some frustrations, like the pancake fiasco; in which Jenney became very angry when she couldn’t remember to wait until the pancakes were cooked a bit more before flipping them, and things about technology (her computer and phone) are still more difficult than they should be. But we’ve had a lot of wins as well; the Occupational Therapist said she was doing great and couldn’t really help any further, Jenney crocheted a new little hat for Marcus and it fit perfectly the first time, the Physical Therapist struggled to find anything to really help Jenney with, her energy increases daily as evidenced by not needing naps during the day any more and taking longer walks, and her capabilities and confidence of taking care of Marcus during the day also increase daily. We can hold standard conversations again (which I’m ever so grateful for) and she has proven that she can do some cooking, do the laundry, make the bed, shower and bathe herself, and in all respects function again as a normal human being. She even did a little gardening today :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This woman is a fighter, with super human healing powers gifted from God. Her army of angels must be strong indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday we started immunotherapy. This is the systemic treatment (similar to chemotherapy but much more modern) which is a series of drugs geared to boost her own immune system in a way that allows her white blood cells to attack the cancer throughout her body and her brain. We have a lot of hope for this treatment and have talked to cancer survivors who have gone through this treatment and have been cancer free for 10 to 15 years now. The clinic does not allow me to be with her while she’s receiving the IV, so I walked around the outside of the hospital for a while, read by the pond they have there, took a short nap in the van, and texted with her while waiting. The first dose took an hour, then we had to wait another hour for the second one to actually arrive (hopefully that doesn’t happen each time) and about another hour for the second dose and flush. It was pretty emotional for her, sitting in the waiting room and reading through the pamphlets of information they hand out, seeing other cancer patients walk in… it’s all becoming very real now for her as it sinks in. So much of the past 4 months she has forgotten due to the surgeries, and so sometimes it all feels fresh to her again. But her short term memory has improved a ton, and she remembers the important events, like going to the beach with us, or to the lake on a beautiful afternoon lunch picnic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to find more of those sorts of things for us all to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the treatments started, we’d had a PET scan, and an MRI (once she’d had her staples removed). The PET scan showed at least one more subcutaneous nodule in her thigh, and there’s a debate as to a spot on the outside of one lung, but nothing life-threatening at this time, thank God. The MRI results showed a new growth in a different part of her brain about 6mm (the main tumors had been about 30mm). We’re consulting with our radiation oncologists about a gamma knife treatment for that this week. The immunotherapy should be able to treat this as well but since we don’t know how fast it’s growing, I’m hoping they can use gamma knife while it’s small because she simply cannot do another craniotomy if it grows too large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcus is also doing really well. He weighed 5lbs 7oz last Monday at our pediatrician appointment, so he’s probably close to 6 lbs by now, if not over. He eats relatively well, though he has trouble with swallowing too much air sometimes and has to stop so we can burp him. That can be frustrating as it’s painful for him when he gets that much air, and he’s gassy afterwards which also seems to pain him. It can take an hour to feed him when he’s swallowing air, and then he wants fed again 2 to 3 hours later. He takes around 1.5 to 2oz per feeding, and we have a sweet friend from church donating breast milk which we give him half and half formula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His preemie clothes are almost too small already at a month old, and his cheeks have filled out. He’s no Sebastian (that kid was a huge roley-poley) but he might get there at this rate. He’s got a pretty pleasant demeanor when he’s not gassy or hungry, and is staying awake during the day more and more. I stay up until about 1 or 2am with him for feedings and changings, reading or writing in between, and then Jenney’s mom Jeanne takes over after that. We get naps during the day and the schedule seems to work out pretty well for us. We let Jenney sleep during the night, but I think she’ll be able to take over when Jeanne goes home. I need to go back to work soon, so I hope that the immunotherapy treatments don’t tire her out too much. If they do, I think we can handle it though. I mean, it’s not brain surgery ;) But Marcus is also starting to go a bit longer in between feedings too, sometimes not waking up for 4 hours at a time. That should start to lengthen as his belly grows and he can store more at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/ACtC-3eRzJJ3Sx8A_7j03gH0LzQqMfpcSmszNYgKES-VmNkX_nVuuta8KmQOMeW2v3Yy5Z1S_b6i_NLzJOL9TaXupyOYBYRSz38KyJTQrQ15X6JFuVaYUa7g1RiDX4UiHvMCAqWePqbfdXiXASon5aCjdoWEsA=w1024-h768-no?authuser=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/USrS1bhxkvc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/jenney-journal-26/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/06/jenney-journal-26/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>