<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: work | Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/blog/categories/work/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-29T12:55:22-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Try, Learn, Know and then Teach]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/try-learn-know-and-then-teach"/>
    <updated>2007-08-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/try-learn-know-and-then-teach</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I make cool stuff at work. I learn something every day that makes me excited and in awe that I get paid to learn, and use, while being taught by the most <a href="http://lullabot.com">enigmatic geniuses</a> that I could even call friend, after a month or so of work comradere. Darkness turns to light with the slightest of gestures from the hands of such as these, that one might stop... and wonders how they, <em>themselves</em> could become something of such magnitude... if only they try, learn, know and then teach.</p>

<h3>Try, Learn, Know and then Teach.</h3>


<p>I am a Drupal Developer, and I love my job. And though it's good to be paid to do what I do, so that I might live in our world, and survive, it is so much more rewarding to live by a Basic Standard in a community of individuals that live by a basic oath, simple, plain, and yet oh... so full of meaning. <em>Try, Learn, Know, and then Teach</em>. A creed of this simplicity and magnitude has yet to be developed and aspired to, other then by so many as those that see Open Source as a way of life, a desire, and a monologue to happiness. The principles not only can be seen, and used well, within software development, but of your life in general. An that is what intrigued me the most when I found Drupal.</p>

<h4>Come again?</h4>


<p>I know it sounds somewhat fanatical and naive, but if you think back to your <a href="http://www.peace.ca/kindergarten.htm">kindergarten rules</a>, what is there NOT in Drupal's Open Source Way of Life that could not be applied to a life and how it should be lived? Drupal's success has been attribute to that and succinctly profound. So live on Open Source, live on... those that thought up Open Source, and please, participate and become someone you respect in a community that truly appreciates those that try, learn, know and then teach.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
