<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: my life | Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/categories/my-life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-19T21:14:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://jeradbitner.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another time, another place...]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/content/another-time-another-place"/>
    <updated>2010-09-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/content/another-time-another-place</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jenney and I moved from Austin to Carolina Beach, North Carolina and the past three.5 months have been amazing! It's been like a working vacation. We were right on the beach, with beautiful views, and a personal walkway to the beach which was in a premo-spot. Not a ton of people, lots of waves, and lots of sunshine. We both worked hard, and played hard. It was great and I can honestly say I've lived my 'beach life' dream for at least a while. Chalk another dream up to 'accomplished'!</p>

<p>Today marks the start of ANOTHER adventure. We packed up our life once more and left beautiful Carolina Beach behind. Tonight we wait at Jenney's best friend's (and Maid of Honor's) house before our flight tomorrow for San Diego where we will be for a week, staying at her mother's house before we are wed on Saturday, September 25th. We're both so so so excited to see our friends and family and to celebrate what we've held true in our hearts for the last year; our commitment and love for each other.</p>

<p>After the wedding we'll be flying back to North Carolina to pick up our belonging and drive to Colorado Springs where we will continue our life together. Jenney took the opportunity for a Pediatric job in her field of Occupational Therapy and will be doing more of what she loves. She went to school specifically for pediatrics, but the job market has, until now, dictate she work in Geriatrics instead. As you can imagine, the field of Geriatrics is a bit more sobering than getting to play with children all day, which is part of what she'll be able to do at her new job. The new job is not quite as lucrative as a traveling position, but we will still be doing fine and loving our life.</p>

<p>My past year with Jenney has been the best year of my life, and I'm so looking forward to many, many more with her by my side. -- guess I better write my vows ;)</p>

<p>For some of the great pictures we took on our travel this far, check out our photostreams on Flickr.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/43114238@N03/">Jenney's Photostream</a>
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sirkitree/">Jerad's Photostream</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trip to Austin]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/content/trip-austin"/>
    <updated>2009-12-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/content/trip-to-austin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What an adventure! <a href="http://jenneymarie.net">Jenney</a> got a contract in Austin Texas for her next position doing traveling Occupational Therapy, so we packed up the new Subaru Forester (new to us) and started the long trek from Grand Junction, Colorado to Austin, Texas.</p>

<p>Now it hadn't snowed much at all in Colorado while we were there, but wouldn't it so happen that the day we decide to leave, a huge storm is forecasted to come through! So we set out as early Monday morning as we could (still had a little cleaning to do) and started on our way. It was too far outside of GJ that it started to flurry, and before we arrived in Ouray, we had passed through some areas with some pretty substantial snowfall. But Ouray there was not much of anything on the ground, and the highway pass through the Redridge Mountains was not closed. So even though there was a sign that commercial vehicles were required to have chains, we went against our better judgement and started up the mountain pass instead of staying in Ouray, at the hotspring hotel, like we should have.</p>

<p>The mountains were amazing! Sheer cliff walls and narrow roads all covered in freshly fallen snow... and it kept getting deeper the higher we went. We were listening to the Lord of the Rings soundtrack on our way up, but when I went around a bend and the back of the car slid just the slightest bit, we turned off the majestic but suspenseful music.</p>

<p>We continued up the mountain pass at a whopping 15MPH and when we came to Silverton we decided to keep going. There were some plows on the road, and there were other vehicles traveling, so we thought we could chance it. We made it <em>almost</em> to Durango when I made a slip in judgement, and was going 20MPH instead of 15MPH coming up on a turn, and the vehicle started to slide as I applied the brakes. We slid off the road, still going quite slow, and took out the front passenger side headlight on a tree. The car bounced to the left and the back end of the car then hit the same spot taking out some of the plastic of the rear brake light and bending up my rear bike wheel which was hitched to the bike rack on the back of the car.</p>

<p>The car stalled, I cursed and pounded the steering wheel, Jenney remained quiet.</p>

<p>I got out of the car to inspect the damage, bent the front side panel back down into place, and got back in the car, kicking the snow from my feet. the car took a couple tries to start, but the engine sounded fine. The damage was completely superficial and since we had all wheel drive, the Subaru pulled right out of the snow bank.</p>

<p>We headed the rest of the way to Durango barely going over 15MPH the rest of the way. Talk about trepidation! When we got to Durango, we stopped at a gas station to get some gas, and I asked the cashier if she had heard the forecast. She said they were due to have about 13inches. I asked if there was a way out of Durango that did not involve mountains. She said she didn't know of any. So we drove around town a little while and decided to bunker down at the Adobe hotel, which offerred us an 'early snow rate' of $40/night.</p>

<p>While we were settling in there, Jenney checked her messages and called back her recruiter who informed her that her contract in Austin had been cancelled! Talk about a depressing day. Stressful snowstorm trek through the precarious mountain pass, damage to our new car, stuck in a snow storm in a town we had not planned on being in and new next to nothing about, and now we were on our way to a job that did not exists.</p>

<p>We stayed in Durango for two nights and checked out the town. Walking through the snow was an adventure for Jenney. Coming from San Diego and being a Cali girl most of her life, she had never experienced a foot of snow before and it was very endearing how her face would light up and she made a snow ball, or a little snow man, or fell backwards in the snow to make a snow angel. She also found that it took a bit of skill to actually <em>walk</em> in the snow ;)</p>

<p>On Wednesday the sun came out and we decided to try our luck getting the heck out of Dodge... err.. Durango. What we found was that the roads weren't so bad and the mountains were no where near as bad as the ones we had come in through, so we probably could have pushed through. But, better safe then sorry - and we didn't want to push our luck any more than we already had. So we are glad we waited.</p>

<p>We made it so Santa Fe, New Mexico and decided to stay there for the evening. We still had a headlight out (garages in Durango didn't have the parts available) so we decided no driving at night. We found a wonderful bed and breakfast on Manhattan St. and after getting settled, wandered around town for a while. Nice town, found some good beer, but the highlight was the fireplace and bed at the bed and breakfast. We awoke the next morning so refreshed and much less stressed from the ordeal through the mountains and Durango.</p>

<p>We headed out around 9am, after breakfast, and got all the way to Post, Texas where we decided on another bed and breakfast. It was only a fraction more than a local chain motel and much cleaner and homey. It was a historical building and I cold work in comfort and we slept quite well.</p>

<p>In the morning we got up early and were on the road by 7:30am, making it to Austin by about 1:30pm. We found a hotel as our basecamp to start the apartment hunt and after two days of exploring Austin and searching for temporary housing, we're now staying in some guy's camper that he keeps in his driveway. It's clean, safe, and cheap. A much cheaper home base for now until we figure out what is going on with Jenney's job and where we're going to actually be for the next few months.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Californication]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/content/californication"/>
    <updated>2008-07-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/content/californication</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Drupal, you've done it again... become the vector of change in my life by presenting me with opportunities that are seemingly too good to be true. Last year it was New York and Sony BMG. This year it's San Francisco and a start-up called ParentsClick Network. Just when I thought things couldn't get any better and that maybe I've hit the height of reaching my dreams in life, another one comes within my grasp, and giving in to my free spirit, I jump at the chance to make a dream a reality.</p>

<p><a href="http://tedserbinski.com/">Ted Serbinski</a> is a guy whose progress I've followed since that first <a href="http://jeradbitner.com/node/11">Lullabot class in Rhode island</a>, less than two years ago (1/15/07) when the world of Drupal really opened up to me. He was a Lullabot at the time, teaching theming and some jQuery. He <a href="http://tedserbinski.com/2007/05/24/i-have-left-lullabot">left Lullabot</a> later that year to start a journey into entrepreneurship (and <a href="http://tedserbinski.com/tags/mothersclick">MothersClick</a>) that has started to pan out nicely. I've great respect for his coding skills and believe in his business sense. So when he approached me about a job working with him in San Francisco, a place I've always wanted to live, I was very excited.</p>

<p>After a week of vacation, taking time to think about my priorities while spending time with family and friends in PA, and then meeting with Ted's business partner, <a href="http://www.mothersclick.com/management">Dietrich von Behren</a> who is the Co-founder &amp; Chief Strategy Officer of MothersClick, I felt confident enough to make the jump and reach for a star on the other side of the country.</p>

<p>My last day at Sony BMG is August 7th, 2008. I'll be heading back to PA to spend some more time with my family and friends and then back to Jersey to take care of getting rid of as much of my worldly possessions as possible. Then the week of the 18th Dave and I will be taking a cross country trip to San Francisco along RT 80. We're still looking for good places to stop along the way, so if you have any suggestions that would be wonderful! I'm also still looking for a temporary place to crash in San Fran while I get the lay of the land and figure out where it makes sense to park myself for a year (read: sign a lease).</p>

<p>All in all, I'm very optimistic and I really feel this is the right move. Not only because I can live one of my dreams, but also to learn about starting a business, and everything that entails. Not to mention becoming a better programmer under the tutelage of a master! Wish me luck!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jerad goes to New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/content/jerad-goes-new-york"/>
    <updated>2007-07-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/content/jerad-goes-to-new-york</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So it's been a long time since I've posted, and there has been so much going on in my life. I've moved to New York City to work with Sony BMG making websites for rockstars. I gotta say, it's been a HUGE change for me. My calm, collected country life where I lived all alone in the woods with the ability to go camping in my back yard was replaced by the hustle and bustle of New York City, staying in a studio apartment next to the Empire State building.</p>

<p>I've been searching for an apartment, and there are lots available, but nothing seems to be what I really want and everything is just so expensive. There is one in Hoboken I'm going to be looking at this week and hopefully that will be it, but there is another one close to Hoboken, next to Washington Park, that Dave and I looked at today that was perfect. It's a little more expensive and there is a brokers fee so I may have to borrow from family to get into the place. I really don't want to do that, and would rather have the place in Hoboken so that I can feel like I'm doing it all on my own, but then my bank account still hasn't received my first paycheck from Sony and I'm worried that they haven't setup my direct deposit yet. That means they've mailed my check and I won't get it until Monday or Tuesday, then I have to get it deposited into my account back home. Only after that will i be able to setup the rent.com escrow account in order to get the keys form the guy who owns the place in Hoboken. He's living in Athens Greece, so we have to do it this way. So as you can imagine, with only 9 days or so to get moved and into a place, I'm stressing.</p>

<p>However, there are a few other possibilities, like Dave getting the same benefits as myself and hanging with him wherever Sony puts him, but that's not going to happen before I have to get out of the place I'm at now. So I guess I'm really banking on this place in Hoboken... ah stress...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
