<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: poems | Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/categories/poems/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-06T16:56:18-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://jeradbitner.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Replicate and share]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/27/replicate-and-share/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-27T04:52:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/27/replicate-and-share</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a child I learned how to speak. The sounds I heard my parents produce helped to form coherent thought patterns in which to relate with the world around me. No, yes; good, bad; dog, cat; hot, cold; all sounds that came to mean something to a normal human being. I replicated their sound and shared.</p>

<p>As I grew, I heard birds, singing in the fields. I learned their whistles and they came to me filling me with the wonder and joy of nature. I replicated their sound and shared.</p>

<p>As I grew, I heard songs at church, worshipping an ideal that was greater than oneself. I learned to sing with the choir and through my song, shared those ideals with more people. I replicated their sound and shared.</p>

<p>As I grew, I heard songs on the radio. I learned them and played my instruments. I learned enough to join a band where we played the songs we had learned for people to enjoy. I replicated their sound and shared.</p>

<p>As I grew, I heard songs on the internet. I learned them, learned to love them, and shared them with my friends so that they could love them too. I replicated their sound and shared.</p>

<p>When I went to jail, untried by my government, for doing what has come naturally to me since I came into this world; replicating the sounds I heard, I cringed at the cries of those around me. I replicated their sound...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angel of fire]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/06/angel-of-fire/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-06T18:33:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/06/angel-of-fire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>```
Angel of fire, wings of light
  Visit me in my dreams tonight
  Tell me of love and burning desire
  Caress my lips, set me on fire</p>

<p>Angel of fire, eyes so bright
  See through my soul, feel the fright
  Singe my heart and look for the liar
  Scar on my sould cleanse with your fire
  Transcendance lost on the blackening shame
  Licked by lips that are black from the flame</p>

<p>Angel of fire, cleanse me just right
  Leaving your mark steal through the night
  Tease my mind leaving desire
  Tease my heart scarred by your fire
  Knowing we'll never ever be the same
  Learn from our past, never do this again
```
- AUG '04</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Images]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2011/04/25/images/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2011/04/25/images</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These are from high school. Guess you'd call that about the height of my creativity - or at least when I had the time to do all of this instead of worrying about a paycheck.</p>

<iframe align="center" src="http://www.flickr.com/slideShow/index.gne?set_id=72057594056358798&" frameBorder="0" width="690" scrolling="no" height="690"></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poems]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/poems"/>
    <updated>2011-04-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/poems</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These are also all pretty old and come from the angst and passions of a teenager. I've grow less intense, it seems, over the years as I don't seem to have the knack of this anymore - if ever I really did. Some of it I still find pretty fun, though it's a bit harder to appreciate in a digital medium since part of what made these so interesting was in the way I wrote them. Strange spacings, capitalization's, and pictographs along with the structure were all part of my art form.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beauty.]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/poems/beauty"/>
    <updated>2011-04-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/poems/beauty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre>
           In the eye of the beholder?
  Maybe.                                                    Not?
                      Well...?
           For sure, are my wants.                  Love,
beauty - I behold.
                            You?
           Oh! Matters to me, what you think.
  Love me?                   Love,     me?
                                Yes!
       For a long time, ifn't life.
Teach: Spirit, love; new, responsibility.
                                     pain; past, New way of thought.
                                                      Discipline.
  SPECIAL are YOU!
         i am?
Comprehend...
                       hard to.
       Comfort are you in a rocking world, in a storm
          of sin.
                    Stability...
                              *mind
                              *soul.
                   For sure.
</pre>


<!-- break -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
