<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: poems | Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/blog/categories/poems/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-29T16:31:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Images]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/blog/2011/04/25/images/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/blog/2011/04/25/images</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These are from high school. Guess you'd call that about the height of my creativity - or at least when I had the time to do all of this instead of worrying about a paycheck.</p>

<iframe align="center" src="http://www.flickr.com/slideShow/index.gne?set_id=72057594056358798&" frameBorder="0" width="690" scrolling="no" height="690"></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poems]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/poems"/>
    <updated>2011-04-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/poems</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These are also all pretty old and come from the angst and passions of a teenager. I've grow less intense, it seems, over the years as I don't seem to have the knack of this anymore - if ever I really did. Some of it I still find pretty fun, though it's a bit harder to appreciate in a digital medium since part of what made these so interesting was in the way I wrote them. Strange spacings, capitalization's, and pictographs along with the structure were all part of my art form.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beauty.]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/poems/beauty"/>
    <updated>2011-04-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/poems/beauty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre>
           In the eye of the beholder?
  Maybe.                                                    Not?
                      Well...?
           For sure, are my wants.                  Love,
beauty - I behold.
                            You?
           Oh! Matters to me, what you think.
  Love me?                   Love,     me?
                                Yes!
       For a long time, ifn't life.
Teach: Spirit, love; new, responsibility.
                                     pain; past, New way of thought.
                                                      Discipline.
  SPECIAL are YOU!
         i am?
Comprehend...
                       hard to.
       Comfort are you in a rocking world, in a storm
          of sin.
                    Stability...
                              *mind
                              *soul.
                   For sure.
</pre>


<!-- break -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rust]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/poems/rust"/>
    <updated>2008-12-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/poems/rust</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The cold hard rain dripped down my face, erasing the warmth<br />
&nbsp;&nbsp;only remembrance remained.</p>


<p>So used to the shielding when heat returned<br />
&nbsp;&nbsp;unnoticed and without all the same.</p>


<p>Then brightness shined, a key was found<br />
&nbsp;&nbsp;to try that diligent construct; cold hard lock.</p>


<p>Will it fit; turn that intricate mechanism<br />
&nbsp;&nbsp;surrounding that which has rusted?</p>


<p>I hope.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Swept Away]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/poems/swept-away"/>
    <updated>2008-04-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/poems/swept-away</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Swept away are the remnants of old, smaller dreams thought too impossible now become reality, even though torn<br/>
Reality torn asunder, pulling back the curtain to reveal the secrets of life lived fully, unhindered by shame<br/>
Shameful regrets, swept away, replaced by a new reality, revealed through conscious will and positive karmic energy<br/>
Positive energies flow through willful projections when unhindered by fear, guided by respect and discipline<br/>
Respect being key, replaces that which eats at everyones soul of late, fear and the assumption of security, apathy</br></p>

<br/>


<p>Swept away and free to dream, your life becomes clay in which to mold a destiny, in harmony with the lines which exist<br/>
See the lines, look ahead down that path which your decision may take you to make a wise choice... prosper<br/>
Fear and doubt be swept away, leaving assured security molded by discipline and experience, always increasing, improving<br/>
Constant reshaping of thoughts and patterns of reasoning, learning to optimize, conceptualize, visualize<br/>
Look forward to what is to come, and what will be swept away</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
