<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: geektool | Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/categories/geektool/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-06T16:56:18-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://jeradbitner.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[todo list in node.js and geektool]]></title>
    <link href="http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/05/todo-list-in-node-dot-js-and-geektool/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-05T13:59:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jeradbitner.com/blog/2012/02/05/todo-list-in-node-dot-js-and-geektool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've long had a quick shell script that was a simple todo list based on Jerod Santo's <a href="http://blog.jerodsanto.net/2010/12/minimally-awesome-todos/">Minimally Awesome Todos</a>. It's very minimal, and quite awesome indeed. Even more than loving how minimal it is, I really liked displaying my todos on my desktop through <a href="http://projects.tynsoe.org/en/geektool/">GeekTool</a>.</p>

<p>Then I stumbled onto a <a href="https://github.com/vesln/todo">Node.js version</a> of a todo list and thought I'd give it a shot. I got it setup, but when I wanted to try to display the output through GeekTool, I failed. So I delved into todo list code a bit more and learned quite a lot!</p>

<p>My <a href="https://github.com/vesln/todo/pull/3">first attempt</a> was to simply write the output of the <code>todo ls</code> command to a file. I got an immediate response from the maintainer, <a href="https://github.com/vesln">Veselin Todorov</a> and was encouraged to change the command from <code>write</code> to <code>export</code> and write up a test for the new command as well.</p>

<p>I succeeded in <a href="https://github.com/vesln/todo/pull/4">converting the <code>write</code> command to <code>export</code></a>, and fixed up a small bug with the path of the file I was writing to by default, but thus far have completely failed at writing a test to confirm that the file was written.</p>

<p>The project is currently using <a href="http://sinonjs.org/">Sinon.JS</a> for testing, and even though the API seems pretty robust, and the examples coherent, I'm simply failing at figuring out how to test file creation with it. So far all I have is a stub:</p>

<p>{% gist 1747985 %}</p>

<p>However, it is working well without a test at this point, and I have a pretty todo list on my desktop! :)</p>

<p><img src="https://img.skitch.com/20120205-q32piq2918kutm1autmh6yby4m.png" alt="GeekTool Todos" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
