<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: life | Jerad Bitner]]></title>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-29T16:36:10-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jerad Bitner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jbitner@jeradbitner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Tattoo]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/new-tattoo"/>
    <updated>2008-07-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/new-tattoo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here's the new one!
<img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3151/2694083801_bcba323a65_m.jpg" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Needs and Wants]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/needs-and-wants"/>
    <updated>2008-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/needs-and-wants</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For a long time I've thought that a major distinction in life that people must try to make is the difference between needs and wants. I've told many of my friends that if they just try to make this distinction in their own life, they will live a much happier, balanced life.</p>

<p>I was going through an old hard drive today and found many of my old writings on lots of different topics, but this one just jumped out at me as it is probably one of the most profound truths and holds some of the most engaging questions of life. The entry is dated 1-11-07:</p>

<p><cite>We've got to stop thinking that we are the only ones that matter.</cite>
<cite>Where does one find the strength to accomplish such a feat? What is the formula for molding one's self unto this task? We all want something greater than what we already experience in this life, but we must learn to separate that which we want, from that which is needed. </cite>
<cite>Define what is needed.</cite>
<cite>Can we tell by ourselves what is needed, or is it defined by those around us? Should it be defined by those around us, or by something greater? If by something greater, then what is that greater something? If by those around us, then whom?</cite></p>

<p>I've pondered on these things most of my conscious life, and still look for the answers. I doubt I will ever stop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Swept Away]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/poems/swept-away"/>
    <updated>2008-04-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/poems/swept-away</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Swept away are the remnants of old, smaller dreams thought too impossible now become reality, even though torn<br/>
Reality torn asunder, pulling back the curtain to reveal the secrets of life lived fully, unhindered by shame<br/>
Shameful regrets, swept away, replaced by a new reality, revealed through conscious will and positive karmic energy<br/>
Positive energies flow through willful projections when unhindered by fear, guided by respect and discipline<br/>
Respect being key, replaces that which eats at everyones soul of late, fear and the assumption of security, apathy</br></p>

<br/>


<p>Swept away and free to dream, your life becomes clay in which to mold a destiny, in harmony with the lines which exist<br/>
See the lines, look ahead down that path which your decision may take you to make a wise choice... prosper<br/>
Fear and doubt be swept away, leaving assured security molded by discipline and experience, always increasing, improving<br/>
Constant reshaping of thoughts and patterns of reasoning, learning to optimize, conceptualize, visualize<br/>
Look forward to what is to come, and what will be swept away</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Try, Learn, Know and then Teach]]></title>
    <link href="http://sirkitree.github.com/content/try-learn-know-and-then-teach"/>
    <updated>2007-08-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sirkitree.github.com/content/try-learn-know-and-then-teach</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I make cool stuff at work. I learn something every day that makes me excited and in awe that I get paid to learn, and use, while being taught by the most <a href="http://lullabot.com">enigmatic geniuses</a> that I could even call friend, after a month or so of work comradere. Darkness turns to light with the slightest of gestures from the hands of such as these, that one might stop... and wonders how they, <em>themselves</em> could become something of such magnitude... if only they try, learn, know and then teach.</p>

<h3>Try, Learn, Know and then Teach.</h3>


<p>I am a Drupal Developer, and I love my job. And though it's good to be paid to do what I do, so that I might live in our world, and survive, it is so much more rewarding to live by a Basic Standard in a community of individuals that live by a basic oath, simple, plain, and yet oh... so full of meaning. <em>Try, Learn, Know, and then Teach</em>. A creed of this simplicity and magnitude has yet to be developed and aspired to, other then by so many as those that see Open Source as a way of life, a desire, and a monologue to happiness. The principles not only can be seen, and used well, within software development, but of your life in general. An that is what intrigued me the most when I found Drupal.</p>

<h4>Come again?</h4>


<p>I know it sounds somewhat fanatical and naive, but if you think back to your <a href="http://www.peace.ca/kindergarten.htm">kindergarten rules</a>, what is there NOT in Drupal's Open Source Way of Life that could not be applied to a life and how it should be lived? Drupal's success has been attribute to that and succinctly profound. So live on Open Source, live on... those that thought up Open Source, and please, participate and become someone you respect in a community that truly appreciates those that try, learn, know and then teach.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
